<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Introduction on Recipes</title><link>/</link><description>Recent content in Introduction on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:05:03 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Iced Orange Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/iced-orange-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 12:05:03 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/iced-orange-cookies/</guid><description>Orange Cookies # Ingredients # Cookies # 1 cup butter Juice of 1 orange 2 cups white granulated sugar 2 large eggs 4 1/2 cups of white flour 1 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. baking powder 1 cup buttermilk Icing # Juice of 1/2 orange 4 cups of powdered sugar 2 Tbsp. butter, melted Instructions # Cookies # Preheat oven to 350°F Cream butter, orange juice, and sugar in a large mixing bowl Add eggs into butter, orange juice, and sugar mix and incorporate well In a separate bowl, sift in flour, baking soda, and baking powder.</description></item><item><title>White Chicken Chili</title><link>/docs/dinner/white-chicken-chili/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:39:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/white-chicken-chili/</guid><description>White Chicken Chili # Ingredients # 1 tbsp. neutral oil 1 medium yellow onion, chopped 1 jalapeño, seeded, finely chopped 2 cloves garlic, finely chopped 1 tsp. dried oregano 1 tsp. ground cumin 3 boneless, skinless chicken breasts, cut into thirds 5 c. low-sodium chicken broth 2 (4.5-oz.) cans green chiles Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper 2 (15-oz.) cans white beans, drained, rinsed 1 1/2 c. frozen corn 1/2 c.</description></item><item><title>Rainbow Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/rainbow-cookies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:23:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/rainbow-cookies/</guid><description>Rainbow Cookies # Ingredients # 1 1/2 cups unsalted butter softened divided (340g) 1 cup granulated sugar (200g) 1 (8-ounce/227g) package almond paste 4 large eggs separated 1 1/2 teaspoons almond extract 2 cups all-purpose flour (240g) 1/4 teaspoon salt red food coloring green food coloring 1/2 cup raspberry jam (160g) 1 1/2 cups semi-sweet chocolate chips (312g) Equipment Needed # 3 (9×13″) baking sheets Large mixing bowls Electric hand or stand mixer Parchment paper Plastic wrap Various weights (canned food works!</description></item><item><title>Slow Cooker French Dip Sandwiches</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:21:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches/</guid><description>Slow Cooker French Dip Sandwiches # Ingredients # 2 1/2 cups low-sodium beef broth 1/4 cup low sodium soy sauce 1 1/2 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce 1 1/2 tsp honey 3 lbs chuck roast Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 1/2 Tbsp olive oil 1 sprig fresh rosemary 1 sprig fresh thyme (use a big sprig with several stems) 1 large yellow onion, sliced 6 cloves garlic, minced (2 Tbsp) 6 Crusty hoagie buns (smaller ones) or 2 crusty baguettes cut into thirds 3 Tbsp butter 6 deli slices provolone or swiss cheese halved Equipment Needed # 6 qt.</description></item><item><title>Slow Cooker Pot Roast</title><link>/docs/dinner/slow-cooker-pot-roast/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:17:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/slow-cooker-pot-roast/</guid><description>Slow Cooker Pot Roast # Ingredients # 1 1/2 Tbsp olive oil, divided 1 (3 lb) chuck roast Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 medium yellow onion, peeled, halved and cut into thick slices 5 garlic cloves, minced (1 1/2 Tbsp) 1 1/4 cups beef broth 2 tsp Worcestershire sauce 1 Tbsp minced fresh thyme 1 Tbsp minced fresh rosemary 2.5 lbs small yukon gold potatoes, left whole 5 medium carrots (about 1 lb), peeled and cut into 1-inch pieces 2 1/2 Tbsp cornstarch mixed with 3 Tbsp beef broth, optional, for thickening - gravy Equipment Needed # 6 qt.</description></item><item><title>Cacio e Pepe</title><link>/docs/pastas/cacio-e-pepe/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:10:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/cacio-e-pepe/</guid><description>Cacio e Pepe # Ingredients # 4 tablespoons (60ml) extra-virgin olive oil, divided 1 teaspoon coarsely ground black pepper, to taste Kosher salt, to taste 1/2 pound (225g) spaghetti 2 tablespoons (30g) unsalted butter 2 ounces Pecorino Romano cheese (about 1 cup; 55g), very finely grated on a Microplane or the smallest holes of a box grater, plus more for serving Equipment Needed # Tablespoon measuring spoon 1 medium skillet 1 large skillet Instructions # Heat 3 tablespoons olive oil and about a teaspoon of black pepper in a medium skillet over medium-low heat until ingredients are fragrant and pepper is barely starting to sizzle, about 1 minute.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Pie</title><link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-pie/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:55:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-pie/</guid><description>Chocolate Pie # Ingredients # 4 ounce package of Baker&amp;rsquo;s German sweet chocolate bar 1/3 cup milk 2 Tbsp. granulated white sugar 3 ounces cream cheese, softened 8 ounces Cool Whip 1 packaged graham cracker crust Equipment Needed # Stand mixer with beater attachment 1 cup measuring cup Spatula Instructions # Heat chocolate and milk in the microwave to melt chocolate. Beat sugar into cream cheese until creamy. Add milk and melted chocolate mixture into the sugar and cream cheese mixture and beat until smooth.</description></item><item><title>Candied Sweet Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/candied-sweet-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:35:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/candied-sweet-potatoes/</guid><description>Candied Sweet Potatoes # Ingredients # 6 yellow-fleshed sweet potatoes 1/2 cup butter or margarine 1 cup packed light brown sugar 1/2 cup water 1 tsp. salt Equipment Needed # Large pot for boiling sweet potatoes 9x13 baking dish Small sauce pan 1 cup measuring cup 1 tsp. measuring sppon Instructions # Boil whole sweet potatoes until tender (approximately 30 to 45 minutes). Drain and cool. Preheat oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>Deviled Eggs</title><link>/docs/sides/deviled-eggs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:35:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/deviled-eggs/</guid><description> Deviled Eggs # Ingredients # 12 large eggs, hard-boiled 3 heaping tbsp. mayonnaise or Miracle Whip 3 squirts of French&amp;rsquo;s yellow mustard Salt and pepper to taste Equipment Needed # Tbsp. measuring spoon Piping bag (optional) Large mixing bowl Instructions # Cut eggs in half, remove yolks and set aside in a mixing bowl Add mustard and mayonnaise to mixing bowl with yolks and mix together Add salt and pepper to taste Either fill the void in the eggs with dollops of the yolk mixture or pipe it into the void Refrigerate for at least an hour Serve chilled</description></item><item><title>Ice Cream Cake Crumble</title><link>/docs/desserts/ice-cream-cake-crumble/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:15:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/ice-cream-cake-crumble/</guid><description> Ice Cream Cake Crumble # Ingredients # 24 Oreo cookies, crushed 7.25-ounce bottle Magic Shell ice cream topping Instructions # Pour the Magic Shell topping over the cookie crumbs and mix well to combine.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Salad With Pepperoni</title><link>/docs/sides/pasta-salad-with-pepperoni/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:05:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/pasta-salad-with-pepperoni/</guid><description>Pasta Salad With Pepperoni # Ingredients # 8 oz. mozzarella cheese, cubed 3/4 cup pepperoni, cubed or sliced thin 1/2 cup grated parmigiano reggiano 1 (16 oz.) package, pasta of choice, cooked and drained 8 oz. cherry tomatoes, halved 3/4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 1/2 cup red wine vinegar 3 tsp Italian seasoning 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp onion powder 1/2 tsp red pepper flakes, optional kosher salt and freshly ground pepper, to taste Equipment Needed # Large bowl Instructions # Combine all dry ingredients in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Broccoli Chicken Casserole</title><link>/docs/dinner/broccoli-chicken-casserole/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 17:54:07 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/broccoli-chicken-casserole/</guid><description>Broccoli Chicken Casserole # Ingredients # 1 package (6 ounces) chicken stuffing mix 2 cups cubed cooked chicken (~1/2&amp;quot; x ~1/2&amp;quot; inch cubes) 1 cup frozen broccoli florets, thawed 1 can (10-3/4 ounces) condensed broccoli cheese soup, undiluted 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese Equipment Needed # 11x7-in. baking dish Large bowl Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°. Prepare stuffing mix according to package directions, using only 1-1/2 cups water. In a large bowl, combine chicken, broccoli, and soup; transfer to a greased 11x7-in.</description></item><item><title>White Chocolate Orange</title><link>/docs/cookies/white-chocolate-orange-cookies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 17:46:50 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/white-chocolate-orange-cookies/</guid><description>Makes ~3 dozen cookies Ingredients # 1 cup unsalted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed brown sugar 1 large egg 1 Tbsp. orange zest 2 1/4 cups all-purpose flour 3/4 tsp. baking soda 1/2 tsp. salt 2 cups white chocolate chips Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Stir flour, baking soda, and salt together in a separate bowl. Set aside. Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in egg and orange zest Gradually mix flour mixture into butter mixture.</description></item><item><title>Pesto</title><link>/docs/pastas/pesto/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 17:37:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/pesto/</guid><description>Pesto # Ingredients # 2 cups of basil leaves 2 Tbsp. of pine nuts 2 large cloves of garlic 1/2 cup olive oil 1/2 finely grated parmesan cheese 8 oz. of gemelli pasta Equipment Needed # Food processor Instructions # Mince basil leaves, pine nuts, and garlic cloves in a food processor. With the food processor running, slowly add the olive oil until smooth. Add the parmesan cheese into the pesto and run the food processor just until incorporated.</description></item><item><title>Steamed Boiled Eggs</title><link>/docs/breakfast/steamed-boiled-eggs/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 08:17:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/breakfast/steamed-boiled-eggs/</guid><description>Steamed Boiled Eggs # Ingredients # (Optional) 1 tray of ice cubes 6 large eggs Equipment Needed # Large pot Steamer insert Instructions # If serving eggs cold, add 1 tray of ice cubes to a large bowl and fill with water. Add 1 inch of water to a large pot. Place steamer insert inside, cover, and bring to a boil over high heat. Add eggs to steamer basket, cover, and continue cooking, 7 minutes for soft-boiled eggs or 14 minutes for hard-boiled.</description></item><item><title>Brocolli Cheddar Soup</title><link>/docs/soups/brocolli-cheddar-soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 07:58:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/soups/brocolli-cheddar-soup/</guid><description>Brocolli Cheddar Soup # Ingredients # 1/4 cup melted butter 1/2 medium chopped onion 1/4 cup flour 2 cups half-and-half cream 2 cups chicken stock or broth 1/2 lb broccoli (about 3 cups), chopped into bite size pieces 1 cup carrot, julienned 1/8 tsp. nutmeg 1/4 tsp. paprika 8 ounces grated sharp cheddar cheese Salt and pepper to taste Equipment Needed # 1 cup measuring cup 1/4 cup measuring cup 2 cup liquid measuring cup 1/4 tsp.</description></item><item><title>Chicago Mild Sauce</title><link>/docs/sauces/chicago-mild-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 07:54:08 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sauces/chicago-mild-sauce/</guid><description> Chicago Mild Sauce # Makes 1 cup Ingredients # 1/2 cup ketchup 1/4 cup barbeque sauce 1 Tbsp. &amp;amp; 1 1/2 tsp. vinegar-based hot sauce 1 Tbsp. yellow mustard Equipment Needed # Small mixing bowl 1/2 cup measuring cup 1/4 cup measuring cup 1 Tbsp. measuring spoon 1 tsp. measuring spoon 1/2 tsp. measuring spoon Instructions # Combine all ingredients and chill overnight.</description></item><item><title>Dill Pickle Dip</title><link>/docs/appetizers/dill-pickle-dip/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 07:48:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/appetizers/dill-pickle-dip/</guid><description>Dill Pickle Dip # Ingredients # 8 ounces cream cheese; softened 1/4 cup dill pickle juice 1/4 cup finely chopped dill pickles 1 Tbsp. chopped fresh dill Equipment Needed # Medium mixing bowl 1 cup dry measuring cup 1/4 cup liquid measuring cup 1 Tbsp. measuring spoon Large spoon for mixing Instructions # Stir cream cheese until smooth. Gradually add pickle juice into the cream cheese, mixing well after each addition.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Tortilla Soup</title><link>/docs/soups/chicken-tortilla-soup/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 06:11:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/soups/chicken-tortilla-soup/</guid><description>Chicken Tortilla Soup # Ingredients # 2 tablespoons vegetable oil 1 small onion, diced 2 tablespoons minced garlic 2 jalapenos, finely diced 6 cups low-sodium chicken broth One 14.5-ounce can fire-roasted diced tomatoes One 14.5-ounce can black beans, rinsed and drained 3 chicken breasts, boneless and skinless 2 limes, juiced, plus wedges for garnish Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1 cup roughly chopped fresh cilantro leaves Equipment Needed # Large stock pot Tablespoon measuring spoon Instructions # In a large stock pot heat the vegetable oil.</description></item><item><title>Nut Horns</title><link>/docs/desserts/nut-horns/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 18:52:22 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/nut-horns/</guid><description>Nut Horns # Makes ~3 dozen cookies Ingredients # Dough # 1 1/4 cups flour 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. salt 3 Tbsp. unsalted butter 3 oz. cream cheese 1/4 cup granulated sugar 1 egg yolk 1/2 tsp. vanilla extract Flour for rolling out dough Filling # 1 cup ground walnuts 1 egg white 1/2 cup granulated sugar Equipment Needed # Stand mixer 1 cup measuring cup 1/2 cup measuring cup 1/4 cup measuring cup 1/2 tsp.</description></item><item><title>Hush Puppies</title><link>/docs/sides/hush-puppies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 18:40:58 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/hush-puppies/</guid><description>Hush Puppies # Ingredients # 1 1/2 cups fine or medium grind cornmeal 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoons kosher salt 1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 teaspoon granulated sugar (optional) 1/2 small yellow onion 1 large egg 1 cup buttermilk 4 cups peanut or vegetable oil, for deep frying Equipment Needed # 1/2 cup measuring cup 1 tsp. measuring spoon 1/2 tsp. measuring spoon Whisk Spatula Box grater Large mixing bowl Dutch oven Size 40 cookie scoop Large plate Metal tongs Spider Instructions # Prepare plate for draining hush puppies.</description></item><item><title>Creamy Tuscan Chicken</title><link>/docs/dinner/creamy_tuscan_chicken/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 17:50:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/creamy_tuscan_chicken/</guid><description>Creamy Tuscan Chicken # Ingredients # 1 tablespoon extra-virgin olive oil 4 boneless skinless chicken breasts (or 2 large ones, halved) Kosher salt Freshly ground black pepper 1 teaspoon dried oregano 3 tablespoons butter 3 cloves minced garlic 1 1/2 cup cherry tomatoes, halved 3 cups baby spinach 1/2 cup heavy cream 1/4 cup freshly grated Parmesan cheese Lemon wedges for serving (optional) Equipment Needed # Skillet Liquid measuring cup 1/4 cup dry measuring cup Measuring spoons Instructions # In a skillet over medium heat, heat oil.</description></item><item><title>Cottage Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/cottage-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 14:13:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/cottage-potatoes/</guid><description>Cottage Potatoes # Ingredients # 2 lb bag of frozen shredded hashbrown potatoes 1/2 cup (1 stick) butter 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon pepper 1 onion, chopped 1 can cream of mushroom soup 1 pint sour cream 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese 1 cup corn flake crumbs or shredded cheddar cheese for topping, according to preference Equipment Needed # Large saute pan 9x13 baking dish Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F In saute pan, use butter to caramelize onion.</description></item><item><title>Sage and Sausage Stuffing</title><link>/docs/sides/sage-and-sausage-stuffing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:28:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/sage-and-sausage-stuffing/</guid><description>Sage and Sausage Stuffing # Ingredients # 1 1/4 pounds high-quality sandwich bread or soft Italian or French bread (about 1 loaf), cut into 3/4-inch dice (about 2 1/2 quarts) 4 Tbsp. butter 3/4 pound sage sausage removed from casing 1/2 large onion, finely chopped (175g) 2 large ribs celery, finely chopped (175g) 1 clove garlic, minced or grated on a Microplane grater 1 tsp. dried sage leaves 2 cups of turkey stock divided into 1 cup portions 2 large eggs 1 Tbsp.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Cherry Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/chocolate-cherry-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 14:05:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/chocolate-cherry-cookies/</guid><description>Chocolate Cherry Cookies # Ingredients # Makes ~3 dozen cookies Cookies # 1/2 cup butter softened 1 cup sugar 1 egg 1 1/2 teaspoon vanilla 1 1/2 cups flour 1/2 cup cocoa powder 1/4 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon baking soda 1 16 oz jar maraschino cherries Topping # 6 oz semi-sweet chocolate chips 1/2 cup sweetened condensed milk 4 teaspoons maraschino cherry juice (can substitute brandy or rum) Equipment Needed # Large mixing bowl Medium mixing bowl Mixer Sifter Small bowls to drain &amp;amp; de-stem cherries Sauce pan Kitchen scale (for chocolate chips) Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Beat together butter and sugar until fluffy.</description></item><item><title>Libby's Famous Pumpkin Pie</title><link>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-pie/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2022 14:05:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-pie/</guid><description>Libby&amp;rsquo;s Famous Pumpkin Pie # Ingredients # 1 can (15 oz) Libby&amp;rsquo;s 100% Pure Pumpkin 1 1/2 cups (12 fl. oz) Evaporated milk 3/4 cup sugar 1/2 teaspoon salt 1 teaspoon ground cinnamon 1/2 teaspoon ground ginger 1/4 teaspoon ground cloves 2 large eggs 1 unbaked 9-inch deep-dish pie shell Equipment Needed # Small mixing bowl Large mixing bowl Hand mixer Pie pan (if not using pre-made pie shell that comes in a pan) Instructions # Preheat oven to 425°F Mix dry ingredients together in small mixing bowl Beat eggs in large mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Buttermilk Biscuits</title><link>/docs/breads/buttermilk-biscuits/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Nov 2022 05:55:18 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/breads/buttermilk-biscuits/</guid><description>Buttermilk Biscuits # Ingredients # 2 cups flour plus more for surface 2 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 tsp. sugar 1/2 tsp. salt 1/3 cup cold butter, shredded 1 cup buttermilk, reduce to 3/4 cup if using an additional liquid flavoring such as maple syrup Egg wash - 1 egg yolk beaten with 1 Tbsp. of water Optional: 1/2 cup of maple syrup for maple biscuits Equipment Needed # Rolling pin 2-cup measuring cup 1/3 cup, 1 tsp.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Mint Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/chocolate-mint-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 18:05:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/chocolate-mint-cookies/</guid><description>Chocolate Mint Cookies # Makes ~2 dozen cookies Ingredients # 6 Tbsp. butter 3/4 cups packed brown sugar 1 tablespoons water 1 cups semisweet chocolate chips 1 eggs 1 1/4 cups all-purpose flour 5/8 teaspoons baking soda 1/4 teaspoon salt 12 Andes Crème De Menthe; unwrapped broken and in half Equipment Needed # Cookie scoop Stand mixer Cookie sheets Instructions # In a large pan over low heat, cook butter, sugar and water until butter is melted.</description></item><item><title>Burst Cherry Tomato Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/burst-cherry-tomato-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 17:50:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/burst-cherry-tomato-pasta/</guid><description>Burst Cherry Tomato Pasta # Ingredients # 1/2 cup extra-virgin olive oil, plus more for drizzling 6 garlic cloves, smashed 2 1/2 lb. cherry tomatoes (about 4 pints) 2 large sprigs basil, plus 1 cup basil leaves, torn if large 3/4 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt, plus more Pinch of sugar (optional) 12 oz. casarecce or other medium-size pasta 1 oz. Parmesan, finely grated (about ½ cup), plus more for serving Equipment Needed # 2 large pots Instructions # Heat /1 cup oil in a large heavy pot over low.</description></item><item><title>Parmesan Spinach Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/parmesan-spinach-pasta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:21:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/parmesan-spinach-pasta/</guid><description>Parmesan Spinach Pasta # Ingredients # 1 13.25 oz package thin spaghetti 8 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided into 1 and 7 Tbsp. 2 garlic cloves, minced 1/2 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 6 cups spinach 4 Tbsp. lemon juice 1/2 cup parmesan cheese 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. pepper Instructions # Cook and drain pasta per package instructions to al dente Add 1 Tbsp. olive oil into the pot the pasta was cooked in.</description></item><item><title>Halushki</title><link>/docs/dinner/halushki/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:16:39 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/halushki/</guid><description>Halushki # Ingredients # 14 oz. Polska kielbasa, sliced 1/4 inch thick 1 large yellow onion, sliced 1/2 head of green cabbage, sliced thin 1/2 bunch fresh parsley, chopped 1 lb. egg noodles 4 oz. unsalted butter Instructions # Cook noodles according to package instructions. While noodles are cooking, melt 2 tablespoons of the butter in a large skillet on medium heat. Add the kielbasa and cook until browned all around.</description></item><item><title>One Skillet Chicken Pot Pie</title><link>/docs/dinner/one-skillet-chicken-pot-pie/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:07:49 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/one-skillet-chicken-pot-pie/</guid><description>One Skillet Chicken Pot Pie # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 1/2 lb boneless skinless chicken breast, cubed 1/2 medium white onion, chopped 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 cup yukon gold potato, cubed 1 cup frozen peas 1 cup frozer carrot 4 Tbsp. butter 4 Tbsp. all-purpose flour 2 cups chicken broth 1 frozen prepared pie crust, thawed 1 egg, beaten Equipment Needed # 1 Tbsp. measuring spoon Cast iron skillet Instructions # Heat the oil in a cast-iron skillet.</description></item><item><title>Salted Caramel Stuffed Double Chocolate Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/salted-caramel-stuffed-double-chocolate-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:43:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/salted-caramel-stuffed-double-chocolate-cookies/</guid><description>Salted Caramel Stuffed Double Chocolate Cookies # Ingredients # 1 cup flour 2/3 cup cocoa powder 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/2 tsp. salt 10 Tbsp. unsalted butter softened 3/4 cup brown sugar 1/4 cup sugar 1 egg at room temperature 2 tsp. vanilla extract 1 1/4 cups semi sweet chocolate chips 18 Rolo candies, unwrapped 1 Tbsp. coarse sea salt OR sea salt flakes Equipment Needed # 1/2 tsp. measuring spoon 1 tsp.</description></item><item><title>Sugar Cookie Frosting</title><link>/docs/cookies/sugar-cookie-frosting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:29:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/sugar-cookie-frosting/</guid><description>Sugar Cookie Frosting # Ingredients # 1 cup unsalted butter softened to cool room temp 3 cups powdered sugar 1 Tbsp. half and half or milk* plus more as needed 1 3/4 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1/8 tsp. salt Equipment Needed # KitchenAid mixer Instructions # Beat butter and half of the powdered sugar until well-combined (starting out the mixer low and increasing to medium-high). Slowly add the remaining powdered sugar (while beating), followed by vanilla extract, salt, and milk.</description></item><item><title>Sugar Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/sugar-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jan 2022 13:20:26 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/sugar-cookies/</guid><description>Sugar Cookies # Ingredients # 2 and 1/4 cups (281g) all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. salt 3/4 cup (1.5 sticks or 170g) unsalted butter, at room temperature 3/4 cup (150g) granulated sugar 1 large egg, at room temperature 2 tsp. pure vanilla extract Equipment Needed # 1/2 tsp. measuring spoon 1/4 tsp. measuring spoon 1 tsp. measuring spoon KitchenAid mixer Rolling pin Cookie sheets Instructions # Whisk the flour, baking powder, and salt together in a medium bowl.</description></item><item><title>Baked Cheese Sticks</title><link>/docs/appetizers/baked-cheese-sticks/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:01:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/appetizers/baked-cheese-sticks/</guid><description>Baked Cheese Sticks # Ingredients # 12 mozzerella string cheese sticks 1/2 cup flour 1/4 cup corn starch 2 eggs 2 Tbsp. olive oil 3/4 cup italian bread crumbs 1/2 cup panko bread crumbs Equipment Needed # 3 shallow dishes 1 baking sheet 1/2 cup measuring cup 1/4 cup measuring cup 1 Tbsp. measuring spoon Instructions # Open the cheese strings and place in the freezer for 2 hours or until completely frozen Preheat oven to 400°F.</description></item><item><title>Chicken Noodle Soup</title><link>/docs/soups/chicken-noodle-soup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 17:37:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/soups/chicken-noodle-soup/</guid><description>Chicken Noodle Soup # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. vegetable oil 1 garlic clove, chopped 1/2 cup chopped onion 1 cup carrots, sliced 1/2 cup celery, finely sliced 2 bay leaves 4 cups cooked chicken meat, shredded 2 quarts chicken broth 6 oz No Yolks Extra Broad Noodles 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp ground black pepper Equipment Needed # Large pot Instructions # Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description></item><item><title>Meatballs</title><link>/docs/dinner/meatballs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 16:36:01 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/meatballs/</guid><description>Meatballs # Ingredients # 1 lb ground beef 1 egg 1/4 cup milk 1/2 cup seasoned breadcrumbs 1/2 tsp. salt 1 tsp. oregano 1 Tbsp. parsley 1/2 tsp. garlic powder 1/4 tsp. fresh ground pepper 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese Equipment Needed # Mixing bowl Baking sheet Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F. Mix all ingredients in bowl by hand. Roll meatballs into golf ball sized balls and place onto a baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>Baked Zucchini</title><link>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 16:31:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</guid><description>Baked Zucchini # Ingredients # 2 medium zucchini 2 eggs 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese 1 cups seasoned bread crumbs Equipment Needed # Cooling rack Rimmed baking sheet Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F. Coat a cooling rack with nonstick spray and place on a rimmed baking sheet. Trim ends off zucchini and slice into 1⁄4&amp;quot; circles. Beat eggs in a small bowl or dish. In a separate bowl or dish, combine parmesan cheese, bread crumbs and salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Wedding Chicken</title><link>/docs/dinner/wedding-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 20:00:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/wedding-chicken/</guid><description>Wedding Chicken # Ingredients # 3/4 - 1 lb. chicken breast 75 ml olive oil 1/2 tsp. dried oregano 1/2 tsp. dried basil 3/8 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. pepper Instructions # Pound chicken with mallet until uniformly 1/2&amp;quot; thick Combine olive oil, oregano, basil, salt, and pepper into a 1 gallon zipper bag Place 2-4 chicken breasts in zipper bag and massage the marinade until chicken is evenly coated. Seal the bag and place in fridge for 4-24 hours.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Roasted Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:48:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</guid><description>Garlic Roasted Potatoes # Ingredients # 3 lb. small red potatoes 1/4 cup olive oil 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt 1 tsp. freshly ground black pepper 2 Tbsp. minced garlic Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Place the potatoes, olive oil, kosher salt, and freshly ground black pepper into a bowl. Toss until well coated. Transfer the potatoes to a sheet pan and roast in the oven for 45 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Fuddruckers Hamburger Seasoning</title><link>/docs/seasonings/fuddruckers-hamburger-seasoning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:45:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/seasonings/fuddruckers-hamburger-seasoning/</guid><description> Fuddruckers Hamburger Seasoning # Ingredients # 1 tsp. paprika 3/4 tsp. ground black pepper 1/2 + 1/8 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. brown sugar 1/8 tsp. garlic powder 1/8 tsp. onion powder 1/8 tsp. ground cayenne pepper Instructions # Combine all ingredients in bowl</description></item><item><title>Whipped Cream</title><link>/docs/desserts/whipped-cream/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:35:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/whipped-cream/</guid><description> Whipped Cream # Ingredients # 1/2 cup cold heavy wipping cream 1 Tbsp. confectioners sugar 1/4 tsp. pure vanilla extract Equipment Needed # Hand or stand mixer with a whisk attachment Instructions # Place the ingredients into a mixing bowl and whip on medium-high speed until medium peaks form.</description></item><item><title>Beignets</title><link>/docs/breakfast/beignets/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:45:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/breakfast/beignets/</guid><description>Beignets # Ingredients # 1/4 tsp. dry yeast 2 Tbsp. warm water; 105°F 2 Tbsp. granulated sugar 1 Tbsp. vegetable shortening 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 cup heavy cream 1/2 egg 2 cups (278 grams) all-purpose flour 1/4 cup boiling water Vegetable oil for frying Confectioner&amp;rsquo;s sugar for dusting Instructions # Sprinkle yeast over warm water in a small bowl, stirring to dissolve. Let stand for 5 minutes. Combine sugar, shortening, salt, heavy cream, egg, flour and boiling water in a large bowl; stir in yeast mixture.</description></item><item><title>Parmesan Baked Chicken</title><link>/docs/dinner/parmesan-baked-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:37:35 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/parmesan-baked-chicken/</guid><description>Parmesan Baked Chicken # Ingredients # 4 5-6 oz chicken breasts 1 cup shredded provolone cheese Ranch spread # 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese 1/4 cup ranch dressing Parmesan crumb topping # 1/2 cup Panko bread crumbs 1 tsp. garlic salt 1/3 shredded parmesan cheese 2 Tbsp. melted butter Equipment Needed # Broiler Instructions # Cook your chicken breasts until browned and they have an internal temperature of 165°F In a small mixing bowl, combine the grated parmesan cheese and ranch dressing In a medium mixing bowl, combine the bread crumbs, garlic salt, shredded parmesan cheese, and butter Position rack in center of the oven and preheat the broiler Place the cooked chicken breast on an oven-safe dish or tray.</description></item><item><title>Strawberry Italian Ice</title><link>/docs/desserts/strawberry-italian-ice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:33:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/strawberry-italian-ice/</guid><description> Strawberry Italian Ice # Ingredients # 1 lb. strawberries, cleaned and pitted 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1 Tbsp. lemon juice 1/2 cup water 1-2 trays of ice cubes Equipment Needed # Blender Instructions # Blend strawberries, sugar, lemon juice, and water until the sugar dissolves Add the ice and blend until smooth Pour into a shallow pan and place into the freezer Stir the mixture every 30 minutes; this will take 2-3 hours to thoroughly freeze</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Nice Cream</title><link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-nice-cream/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:29:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-nice-cream/</guid><description> Chocolate Nice Cream # Ingredients # 3 overripe bananas 1/4 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1/8 tsp. salt 3 Tbsp. cocoa powder Equipment Needed # Blender or food processor Instructions # Cut bananas into small rounds, put into an airtight container and freeze for 6+ hours Place all ingredenients into a food processor or blender Blend until a soft serve texture has been reached. Serve immediately or transfer to a freezer safe container and freeze for an additional 30 minutes</description></item><item><title>Buttercream</title><link>/docs/desserts/buttercream/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 09:00:59 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/buttercream/</guid><description>Buttercream # Makes enough buttercream for a 9-inch round 2 layer cake Ingredients # 1 1/2 cups unsalted butter, softened 4 1/2 cups confectioners sugar 3/4 cup unsweetened cocoa powder 3 Tbsp. heavy whipping cream 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1/4 tsp. salt Equipment Needed # Hand or stand mixer with a paddle attachment Instructions # Beat the butter on medium speed for 2-3 minutes until creamy. Add confectioners sugar, heavy cream, vanilla extract, and salt.</description></item><item><title>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</guid><description>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies # Ingredients # Makes 4 dozen cookies 1 egg 1/2 cup white sugar 1/2 cup brown sugar 1/2 cup crisco 1 tsp. vanilla 2 Tbsp. milk 1/2 cup peanut butter 1 3/4 cups flour 1/2 tsp. salt 1 tsp. baking soda 48 Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses extra white sugar for rolling Equipment Needed # Medium mixing bowl Mixer Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) Small bowl of sugar for rolling Large dinner plate for Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses Instructions # Preheat oven to 375 degrees In mixing bowl, cream together the egg, white and brown sugars, and crisco.</description></item><item><title>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid><description>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies # Ingredients # 1 cup shortening 2 cups white sugar 2 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 Tbsp. milk 1 15 oz. can of pumpkin 2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 1 tsp. cinnamon 3 1/2 cups of flour 1 or 2 cups of chocolate chips Equipment Needed # 2 mixing bowls Cookie sheets Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F In a mixing bowl.</description></item><item><title>Zucchini Bread</title><link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:17 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</guid><description>Zucchini Bread # Ingredients # 3 eggs 2 cups sugar 1 cup oil 2 Tbsp. vanilla 2 cups zucchini 2 cups flour 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1 tsp. salt 1 cup chopped nuts (optional) Equipment Needed # Two loaf pans Mixer Medium mixing bowl Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) 1 cup liquid measuring cup 1 cup dry measuring cup Tablespoon Teaspoon 1/4 teaspoon Instructions # Preheat oven to 350 degrees In mixing bowl, beat eggs til frothy Add in sugar, oil, and vanilla.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Brownie Frosting</title><link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:52:20 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</guid><description>Chocolate Brownie Frosting # Ingredients # 1/4 cup butter or margarine 6 Tbsp. cocoa powder 2 cups confectioners&amp;rsquo; sugar 1/4 cup milk 1/2 tsp. of vanilla extract Equipment Needed # 2 mixing bowls Instructions # Melt the butter or margarine and then mix in the cocoa powder. Set aside to cool. In another bowl, blend together the confectioners&amp;rsquo; sugar, milk, and vanilla extract. Slowly beat together the dry and wet ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Zucchini Brownies</title><link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:42:38 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</guid><description>Zucchini Brownies # Ingredients # 1/2 cup vegetable oil 1 1/2 cups white sugar 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1/2 cup unsweetened cocoa powder 1 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on. Equipment Needed # 2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Zucchini Cake</title><link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:24:33 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</guid><description>Zucchini Cake # Ingredients # 1 cup vegetable oil 2 cups sugar 3 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1 tsp. baking soda 1/2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on Equipment Needed # 2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description></item><item><title>Not Cheeseburger Helper</title><link>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 19:17:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</guid><description>Not Cheeseburger Helper # Ingredients # 8 oz medium pasta shells 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 lb. ground beef 1/2 medium sweet onion, diced 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 1/2 tsp. Italian seasoning 2 Tbps. all-purpose flour 2 cups beef stock 15 ounces tomato sauce 3/4 cup heavy cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 6 ounces shredded extra-sharp cheddar cheese Instructions # In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook pasta until it is al dente according to package instructions; drain well.</description></item><item><title>Baked Feta Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 09:26:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</guid><description>Baked Feta Pasta # Ingredients # 8 ounces dried cavatappi pasta 2 pints cherry tomatoes 8 ounce block feta cheese 1/2 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/4 teaspoon sea salt 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 2 garlic cloves, minced 1/4 cup packed chopped fresh basil plus more for serving Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F Place the cherry tomatoes in an oven-safe baking dish. Pour in the olive oil and season with the sea salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Lazy Hand Pies</title><link>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 20:51:14 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</guid><description>Lazy Hand Pies # Ingredients # 1 (9 ounce) box of Jiffy pie crust mix 1 can of pie filling in a flavor of your choosing 1 large egg 1 Tbsp. milk or water Cinnamon or demerara sugar for coating, if desired Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F Line a large baking sheet with parchment paper Prepare the pie crust mix according to the directions on the packaging On a large floured surface, roll out the pie crust until it is around 1/8 inch thick Using a 6 inch round biscuit cutter or flat rimmed bowl, cut the pie crust into 6 rounds and place them on the baking sheet.</description></item><item><title>Instant Pot Pulled Pork</title><link>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-pulled-pork/</link><pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 17:39:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-pulled-pork/</guid><description>Instant Pot Pulled Pork # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. packed brown sugar 2 tsp. paprika 2 tsp. garlic powder 2 tsp. onion powder 1 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pepper 1/2 tsp. cumin 1/4 tsp. cayenne 3 lbs. boneless pork roast, cut into 3-4 inch cubes 2 Tbsp. olive oil 1/3 cup apple cider vinegar 2 cups barbecue sauce, divided into 1 cup portions 1 1/4 cup beef broth, divided into 1 cup and 1/4 cup Instructions # In a small bowl mix together the brown sugar, paprika, garlic powder, onion powder, salt, pepper, cumin, and cayenne.</description></item><item><title>Banana Bread</title><link>/docs/breads/banana-bread/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 19:51:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/breads/banana-bread/</guid><description> Banana Bread # Makes 1 loaf or ~20 muffins Ingredients # 3-4 ripe bananas, mashed 1/3 cup melted butter 1 cup sugar 1 egg, beaten 1 tsp. vanilla extract 1 tsp. baking soda 1/8 tsp. salt 1 1/2 cup flour 1/4 cup of chocolate chips (optional) Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Grease the loaf pan Mix together the butter and bananas Mix in eggs, sugar, and vanilla Mix in baking soda and salt Mix in flour Mix in chocolate chips Pour the mixture into the loaf pan Bake for 45 minutes For muffins, bake for 25 minutes Notes # If edges are real brown and the middle is still jiggly turn the oven down to 325°F and bake in 5 minute increments until the center is no longer jiggly</description></item><item><title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid><description>Fried Chicken Sandwich # Ingredients # ~1 lb. boneless, skinless chicken breast 1 cup dill pickle juice 1 1/2 cups of milk, divided into 1 cup and 1/2 cup 1 3/4 cup peanut or canola oil for frying 1 large egg 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1 Tbsp. powdered sugar 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. ground black pepper For a Spicy Chicken Sandwich # 1/2 tsp. paprika 1 Tbsp. cayenne powder Instructions # Butterfly the chicken breast.</description></item><item><title>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake</title><link>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:27:02 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</guid><description>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake # Ingredients # 1 lb. semisweet chocolate chips 1 lb. unsalted butter, diced 1 cup freshly brewed decaf espresso 1 cup brown sugar 8 whole eggs Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Butter 9-inch cake pan, then line the bottom of the cake pan with parchment paper. Place chocolate chips and butter into a stainless steel mixing bowl. Gently melt over double boiler. Stir well. Place espresso and brown sugar in a sauce pot.</description></item><item><title>Baked Ziti</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:16:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</guid><description>Baked Ziti # Ingredients # 1 pound ziti pasta; cooked al-dente 1 Tbsp. extra virgin olive oil 1 large onion, chopped 4-6 garlic cloves, chopped 1 Tbsp. fresh rosemary or basil, minced 2 Tbsp. Italian seasoning 1/2 tsp. red pepper flakes 32 oz. marinara sauce Salt and pepper to taste 1/2 lb. of mozzarella cheese, shredded 1 cup of ricotta cheese 1 cup grated parmesan cheese Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Heat the olive oil in a large sauce pan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Aglio E Olio</title><link>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:30:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</guid><description> Pasta Aglio e Olio # Ingredients # 1/2 pound of cooked linguine or fettucine pasta 1/4 cup of pasta water 5 - 6 cloves of garlic, thinly sliced 1/8 tsp. red pepper flake 1/2 cup flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped 1/2 cup olive oil 1 lemon worth of juice A pinch of kosher salt A pinch of freshly ground pepper Instructions # Heat the olive oil up in saucepan over medium heat Add the garlic to the saucepan and cook just until the garlic turns blonde Add the red pepper flake, salt, and pepper to the oil and stir to combine Add the pasta and pasta water to the sauce pan and toss to coat Remove the saucepan from heat Add the lemon juice and parsley to the saucepan and stir to combine</description></item><item><title>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken</title><link>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:14:08 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</guid><description>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken # Ingredients # 1 cup chicken stock 1 1/2 lbs chicken 1/4 tsp. onion powder 1/4 tsp. garlic powder 1/4 tsp. paprika 1/4 tsp. salt 3/4 cups BBQ sauce 1/4 cup grated onion, with juice 1 1/2 Tbsp. brown sugar Instructions # Place the ingredients in the instant pot in this order; Do NOT stir, you want the liquid to stay on the bottom of the pot so the instant pot comes to pressure.</description></item><item><title>Potato Soup</title><link>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 19:01:17 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</guid><description>Potato Soup # Ingredients # 6 cups of peeled and diced Russett potates (around 6 medium potatoes. Diced into cubes about 3/4 inch) 1 1/2 cups chopped yellow onion (1 medium onion) 1 1/4 cups peeled and diced carrots (3 medium or 15 baby) 1 cup diced celery (4 stalks) 29 oz low-sodium chicken broth Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1/3 cup butter 1/3 cup all-purpose flour 2 1/2 cups milk 1/2 cup sour cream Instructions # Combine diced potatoes, carrots, celery and onions with chicken broth in a large stockpot and season with salt and pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Semi Active Boy Bagel Bites</title><link>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 17:04:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</guid><description> Semi-Active Boy Bagel Bites # Ingredients # 8 Thomas&amp;rsquo; Plain Mini Bagels, split Pizza sauce Cubed pepporoni Mozzeralla or a pizza cheese blend Salt Pepper Instructions # Adjust over rack to the middle position Preheat oven to 450°F Arrange half of the split bagels on parchment-lined baking sheet Place bagel halves in oven until their surface dries out, around 2.5 minutes Remove bagel halves from the oven and top each bagel half with pizza sauce, a sprinkle of salt, a sprinkle of pepper, a generous mound of cheese, and cubed pepperoni Bake until cheese is melted and golden brown, around 10 minutes Repeat baking steps for any remaining bagel halves</description></item><item><title>Baked Macaroni and Cheese</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 18:23:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</guid><description>Baked Macaroni and Cheese # Ingredients # 16 oz cavatappi or elbow macaroni, cooked and drained 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. pepper 3/4 tsp. dry mustard 1/4 tsp. cayenne pepper 4 Tbsp. butter 4 Tbsp. flour 3 1/2 cups whole milk, warm 5 cups of sharp cheddar cheese, shredded Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Pour cooked macaroni into a 3 qt. baking dish Mix salt, pepper, dry mustard, and cayenne pepper in a small bowl and set aside Melt butter in large saucepan over low heat Stir in flour into the melted butter to form a roux Raise the temperature of the saucepan to medium-high Add the milk to the saucepan and bring to a boil while whisking until the sauce thickens.</description></item><item><title>Brownies</title><link>/docs/desserts/brownies/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 18:44:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/brownies/</guid><description>Brownies # Makes ~9 brownies Ingredients # 200g (1 cup) granulated sugar 40g (1/3 cup) unsweetened cocoa powder sifted 64g (1/2 cup) all-purpose flour 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. baking powder 2 eggs, room temperature 1 tsp. McCormick vanilla 113g (1/2 cup) butter, melted then cooled Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Lightly grease an 8-inch square pan and set aside Sift together the sugar, cocoa powder, flour, salt, and baking powder into a medium bowl In another medium bowl, beat together the eggs with vanilla Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and using a whisk, stir the dry ingredients into the wet.</description></item><item><title>MLTB</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:58:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</guid><description> MLTB # Ingredients # 2 slices bread, toasted 2 slices cooked bacon, broken in half 2 slices tomato 1 slice lettuce 1/2 Tbps. mayonaise Instructions # Place 2 slices of bread on a cutting board. Spread mayonaise on the top slice of bread Place lettuce on the top slice Fan out the slices of bacon on the lower slice of bread Place tomatoes on the bottom slice of bread Place the top half of the sandwich onto the bottom half</description></item><item><title>Fried Pickles</title><link>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:27:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</guid><description>Fried Pickles # Ingredients # 1 16-ounce jar of kosher dill pickles, drained and dried 2/3 cup flour 1 Tbsp. of italian or Old Bay seasoning 1 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 1 egg, beaten Vegtable or canola oil for frying Instructions # Mix the flour, seasoning, red pepper flakes, pinch of salt, and a pinch of ground pepper in a large bowl Place the beaten egg into a small bowl, Dunk the pickles into the egg and then dredge in the flour mixture.</description></item><item><title>Soft Pretzels</title><link>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:17:32 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</guid><description>Soft Pretzels # Ingredients # 1 1/2 cups water, warm (~110°F) 1 Tbsp. salt 1 Tbsp. sugar 1 packet active dry yeast 4 cups (556 grams) flour 2 1/2 Tbsp. butter, melted 10 cups water 1/3 cup baking soda 1 egg yolk beaten with 1 Tbsp. of water coarse salt Equipment Needed # KitchenAid mixer Large stock pot Instructions # In the KitchenAid bowl mix the water, salt, and sugar until combined.</description></item><item><title>Scalloped Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:23:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</guid><description>Scalloped Potatoes # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. butter 2 cloves garlic 1 Tbsp. flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 tsp. pepper 1 cup milk 3 yukon gold potatoes, peeled 2 tbsp. grated parmesan cheese Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F In a small pot, melt the butter and fry the garlic until it’s just starting to brown. Add the flour, salt and pepper. whisk until there are no lumps. Slowly drizzle in the milk while constantly whisking to make sure the mixture is smooth.</description></item><item><title>Big Mac Sauce</title><link>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 16:25:12 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</guid><description> Big Mac Sauce # Ingredients # 1/4 cup of mayonaise 1.5 tsp. sweet pickle relish 3/4 tsp. american mustard 3/4 tsp. white wine vinegar 0.5 tsp onion powder 0.5 tsp garlic powder 0.5 tsp sweet paprika Instructions # Place ingredients into a bowl and mix together</description></item><item><title>Chili</title><link>/docs/dinner/chili/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 20:06:33 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/dinner/chili/</guid><description>Chili # Ingredients # 2 1/2 Tbsp. chili powder 2 Tbsp. ground cumin 2 Tbsp. packed light brown sugar 1 Tbsp. garlic powder 1 1/2 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. ground black pepper 1/4 tsp. ground cayenne pepper 1/8 tsp. ground cinnamon 2 tsp. cocoa powder 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 medium yellow onion - diced 1 medium green bell pepper - diced 1 lb 90% lean ground beef 2 Tbsp.</description></item><item><title>Baked Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:20:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</guid><description> Baked Potatoes # Ingredients # Some number of russet potatoes 1.5 tsp. of olive oil Kosher salt for sprinkling on the exterior of the potatoes Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Scrub potatoes with scrub brush and dab dry Poke the potatoes 5 or 6 times with a fork Brush olive oil on the potatoes and salt the exterior lightly Place potatoes directly on the middle rack of the oven Bake for 45 - 55 minutes</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid><description>Chocolate Chip Cookies # Makes ~3 dozen cookies Ingredients # 1/2 cup salted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1 large egg 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. sea salt 1 cup chocolate chips Instructions # Preheat oven to 375°F Line a baking pan with parchment paper and set aside Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in eggs and vanilla until fluffy Mix in the dry ingredients until combined.</description></item><item><title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid><description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste Instructions # Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description></item><item><title>Sexy Rice</title><link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid><description>Sexy Rice # Ingredients # 2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt Instructions # Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes Notes # When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Ganache Glaze</title><link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:00:06 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</guid><description> Chocolate Ganache Glaze # Ingredients # 3/4 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips 3 Tbsp. butter 1 Tbsp. light corn syrup 1/3 tsp. vanilla Instructions # In a double boiler over hot not boiling water combine chocolate chips, margarine, and corn syrup. Stir until chips are melted and mixture is smooth. Add vanilla and stir. Use the glaze to dip cookies into or to spread over a cake.</description></item><item><title>Chocolate Spice Cookies</title><link>/docs/cookies/chocolate-spice-cookies/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:36:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/cookies/chocolate-spice-cookies/</guid><description>Chocolate Spice Cookies # Ingredients # Makes ~4 dozen cookies with a size 40 scoop 1 cup Crisco 1.5 cup milk 4 cups flour 0.5 cup cocoa 1.5 cup sugar 1 tsp. baking soda 3 tsp. baking powder 0.5 tsp. clove 2 tsp. cinnamon 1 tsp. allspice 3/8 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 0.25 cup chopped walnuts Instructions # Melt Crisco in saucepan with milk and set aside to cool.</description></item></channel></rss>