<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Recipes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:14:08 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken #  Ingredients #   1 cup chicken stock 1 1/2 lbs chicken 1/4 tsp. onion powder 1/4 tsp. garlic powder 1/4 tsp. paprika 1/4 tsp. salt 3/4 cups BBQ sauce 1/4 cup grated onion, with juice 1 1/2 Tbsp. brown sugar  Instructions #   Place the ingredients in the instant pot in this order; Do NOT stir, you want the liquid to stay on the bottom of the pot so the instant pot comes to pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Soup</title>
      <link>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 19:01:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</guid>
      <description>Potato Soup #  Ingredients #   6 cups of peeled and diced Russett potates (around 6 medium potatoes. Diced into cubes about 3/4 inch) 1 1/2 cups chopped yellow onion (1 medium onion) 1 1/4 cups peeled and diced carrots (3 medium or 15 baby) 1 cup diced celery (4 stalks) 29 oz low-sodium chicken broth Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1/3 cup butter 1/3 cup all-purpose flour 2 1/2 cups milk 1/2 cup sour cream  Instructions #   Combine diced potatoes, carrots, celery and onions with chicken broth in a large stockpot and season with salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semi Active Boy Bagel Bites</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 17:04:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</guid>
      <description>Semi-Active Boy Bagel Bites #  Ingredients #   8 Thomas&#39; Plain Mini Bagels, split Pizza sauce Cubed pepporoni Mozzeralla or a pizza cheese blend Salt Pepper  Instructions #   Adjust over rack to the middle position Preheat oven to 450°F Arrange half of the split bagels on parchment-lined baking sheet Place bagel halves in oven until their surface dries out, around 2.5 minutes Remove bagel halves from the oven and top each bagel half with pizza sauce, a sprinkle of salt, a sprinkle of pepper, a generous mound of cheese, and cubed pepperoni Bake until cheese is melted and golden brown, around 10 minutes Repeat baking steps for any remaining bagel halves  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Macaroni and Cheese</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 18:23:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Baked Macaroni and Cheese #  Ingredients #   16 oz cavatappi or elbow macaroni, cooked and drained 2 Tbsp. butter 4 Tbsp. flour 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. pepper 3/4 tsp. dry mustard 3 1/2 cups milk 1/4 tsp. cayenne pepper 5 cups of sharp cheddar cheese, shredded  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Pour cooked macaroni into a 3 qt. baking dish Mix flour, salt, pepper, and mustard in a small bowl and set aside Melt butter in large saucepan over low heat Stir in flour mixture into the melted butter to form a roux Raise the temperature of the saucepan to medium-high Add the milk and cayenne pepper to the saucepan and bring to a boil; while whisking until the sauce thickens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 18:44:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/brownies/</guid>
      <description>Brownies #  Makes ~9 brownies  Ingredients #   200g (1 cup) granulated sugar 40g (1/3 cup) unsweetened cocoa powder sifted 64g (1/2 cup) all-purpose flour 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. baking powder 2 eggs, room temperature 1 tsp. McCormick vanilla 113g (1/2 cup) butter, melted then cooled  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Lightly grease an 8-inch square pan and set aside Sift together the sugar, cocoa powder, flour, salt, and baking powder into a medium bowl In another medium bowl, beat together the eggs with vanilla Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and using a whisk, stir the dry ingredients into the wet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLTB</title>
      <link>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:58:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</guid>
      <description>MLTB #  Ingredients #   2 slices bread, toasted 2 slices cooked bacon, broken in half 2 slices tomato 1 slice lettuce 1/2 Tbps. mayonaise  Instructions #   Place 2 slices of bread on a cutting board. Spread mayonaise on the top slice of bread Place lettuce on the top slice Fan out the slices of bacon on the lower slice of bread Place tomatoes on the bottom slice of bread Place the top half of the sandwich onto the bottom half  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Pickles</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:27:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</guid>
      <description>Fried Pickles #  Ingredients #   1 16-ounce jar of kosher dill pickles, drained and dried 2/3 cup flour 1 Tbsp. of italian or Old Bay seasoning 1 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 1 egg, beaten Vegtable or canola oil for frying  Instructions #   Mix the flour, seasoning, red pepper flakes, pinch of salt, and a pinch of ground pepper in a large bowl Place the beaten egg into a small bowl, Dunk the pickles into the egg and then dredge in the flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Pretzels</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</guid>
      <description>Soft Pretzels #  Ingredients #   1 1/2 cups water, warm (~110°F) 1 Tbsp. salt 1 Tbsp. sugar 1 packet active dry yeast 4 cups flour 2 1/2 Tbsp. butter, melted 10 cups water 1/3 cup baking soda 1 egg yolk beaten with 1 Tbsp. of water coarse salt  Instructions #   In a bowl mix water, salt, and sugar until combined. Add yeast, and let rest 5 minutes until yeast starts to foam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalloped Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:23:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Scalloped Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. butter 2 cloves garlic 1 Tbsp. flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 tsp. pepper 1 cup milk 3 yukon gold potatoes, peeled 2 tbsp. grated parmesan cheese  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F In a small pot, melt the butter and fry the garlic until it’s just starting to brown. Add the flour, salt and pepper. whisk until there are no lumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Mac Sauce</title>
      <link>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 16:25:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Big Mac Sauce #  Ingredients #   1/4 cup of mayonaise 1.5 tsp. sweet pickle relish 3/4 tsp. american mustard 3/4 tsp. white wine vinegar 0.5 tsp onion powder 0.5 tsp garlic powder 0.5 tsp sweet paprika  Instructions #   Place ingredients into a bowl and mix together  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 20:06:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/chili/</guid>
      <description>Chili #  Ingredients #   2 1/2 Tbsp. chili powder 2 Tbsp. ground cumin 2 Tbsp. packed light brown sugar 1 Tbsp. garlic powder 1 1/2 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. ground black pepper 1/4 tsp. ground cayenne pepper 1/8 tsp. ground cinnamon 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 medium yellow onion - diced 1 medium green bell pepper - diced 1 lb 90% lean ground beef 2 Tbsp. tomato paste 1 1/2 cups beef broth 1 (15 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:20:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Baked Potatoes #  Ingredients #   Some number of russet potatoes 1.5 tsp. of olive oil Kosher salt for sprinkling on the exterior of the potatoes  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Scrub potatoes with scrub brush and dab dry Poke the potatoes 5 or 6 times with a fork Brush olive oil on the potatoes and salt the exterior lightly Place potatoes directly on the middle rack of the oven Bake for 45 - 55 minutes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies  Ingredients #   1/2 cup salted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1 large egg 1.5 cups all-purpose flower 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. sea salt 1 cup chocolate chips  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375°F Line a baking pan with parchment paper and set aside Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in eggs and vanilla until fluffy Min in the dry ingredients until combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste  Instructions #   Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexy Rice</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid>
      <description>Sexy Rice #  Ingredients #   2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt  Instructions #   Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes  Notes #   When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Ganache Glaze</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Ganache Glaze #  Ingredients #   3/4 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips 3 Tbsp. butter 1 Tbsp. light corn syrup 1/3 tsp. vanilla  Instructions #   In a double boiler over hot not boiling water combine chocolate chips, margarine, and corn syrup. Stir until chips are melted and mixture is smooth. Add vanilla and stir. Use the glaze to dip cookies into or to spread over a cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Spice Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:36:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Spice Cookies #  Ingredients #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies   1 cup Crisco 1.5 cup milk 4 cups flour 0.5 cup cocoa 1.5 cup sugar 1 tsp. baking soda 3 tsp. baking powder 0.5 tsp. clove 2 tsp. cinnamon 1 tsp. allspice 3/8 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 0.25 cup chopped walnuts  Instructions #   Melt Crisco in saucepan with milk and set aside to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
