<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Introduction on Recipes</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Introduction on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:01:33 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Baked Cheese Sticks</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/baked-cheese-sticks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Dec 2021 09:01:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/baked-cheese-sticks/</guid>
      <description>Baked Cheese Sticks #  Ingredients #   12 mozzerella string cheese sticks 1/2 cup flour 1/4 cup corn starch 2 eggs 2 Tbsp. olive oil 3/4 cup italian bread crumbs 1/2 cup panko bread crumbs  Equipment Needed #   3 shallow dishes 1 baking sheet 1/2 cup measuring cup 1/4 cup measuring cup 1 Tbsp. measuring spoon  Instructions #   Open the cheese strings and place in the freezer for 2 hours or until completely frozen Preheat oven to 400°F.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Noodle Soup</title>
      <link>/docs/soups/chicken-noodle-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 17:37:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/soups/chicken-noodle-soup/</guid>
      <description>Chicken Noodle Soup #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. vegetable oil 1 garlic clove, chopped 1/2 cup chopped onion 1 cup carrots, sliced 1/2 cup celery, finely sliced 2 bay leaves 4 cups cooked chicken meat, shredded 2 quarts chicken broth 6 oz No Yolks Extra Broad Noodles 1/4 tsp salt 1/4 tsp ground black pepper  Equipment Needed #   Large pot  Instructions #   Heat oil in a large pot over medium heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 16:36:01 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/meatballs/</guid>
      <description>Meatballs #  Ingredients #   1 lb ground beef 1 egg 1/4 cup milk 1/2 cup seasoned breadcrumbs 1/2 tsp. salt 1 tsp. oregano 1 Tbsp. parsley 1/2 tsp. garlic powder 1/4 tsp. fresh ground pepper 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese  Equipment Needed #   Mixing bowl Baking sheet  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F. Mix all ingredients in bowl by hand. Roll meatballs into golf ball sized balls and place onto a baking sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Zucchini</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 16:31:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</guid>
      <description>Baked Zucchini #  Ingredients #   2 medium zucchini 2 eggs 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese 1 cups seasoned bread crumbs  Equipment Needed #   Cooling rack Rimmed baking sheet  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F. Coat a cooling rack with nonstick spray and place on a rimmed baking sheet. Trim ends off zucchini and slice into 1⁄4&amp;quot; circles. Beat eggs in a small bowl or dish.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Chicken</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/wedding-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 20:00:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/wedding-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Wedding Chicken #  Ingredients #   3/4 - 1 lb. chicken breast 75 ml olive oil 1/2 tsp. dried oregano 1/2 tsp. dried basil 3/8 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. pepper  Instructions #   Pound chicken with mallet until uniformly 1/2&amp;quot; thick Combine olive oil, oregano, basil, salt, and pepper into a 1 gallon zipper bag Place 2-4 chicken breasts in zipper bag and massage the marinade until chicken is evenly coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:48:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Garlic Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   3 lb. small red potatoes 1/4 cup olive oil 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt 1 tsp. freshly ground black pepper 2 Tbsp. minced garlic  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Place the potatoes, olive oil, kosher salt, and freshly ground black pepper into a bowl. Toss until well coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fuddruckers Hamburger Seasoning</title>
      <link>/docs/seasonings/fuddruckers-hamburger-seasoning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:45:30 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/seasonings/fuddruckers-hamburger-seasoning/</guid>
      <description>Fuddruckers Hamburger Seasoning #  Ingredients #   1 tsp. paprika 3/4 tsp. ground black pepper 1/2 + 1/8 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. brown sugar 1/8 tsp. garlic powder 1/8 tsp. onion powder 1/8 tsp. ground cayenne pepper  Instructions #   Combine all ingredients in bowl  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Whipped Cream</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/whipped-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:35:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/whipped-cream/</guid>
      <description>Whipped Cream #  Ingredients #   1/2 cup cold heavy wipping cream 1 Tbsp. confectioners sugar 1/4 tsp. pure vanilla extract  Equipment Needed #   Hand or stand mixer with a whisk attachment  Instructions #   Place the ingredients into a mixing bowl and whip on medium-high speed until medium peaks form.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beignets</title>
      <link>/docs/breakfast/beignets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:45:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/breakfast/beignets/</guid>
      <description>Beignets #  Ingredients #   1/4 tsp. dry yeast 2 Tbsp. warm water; 105°F 2 Tbsp. granulated sugar 1 Tbsp. vegetable shortening 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 cup heavy cream 1/2 egg 2 cups (278 grams) all-purpose flour 1/4 cup boiling water Vegetable oil for frying Confectioner&amp;rsquo;s sugar for dusting  Instructions #   Sprinkle yeast over warm water in a small bowl, stirring to dissolve. Let stand for 5 minutes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Parmesan Baked Chicken</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/parmesan-baked-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:37:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/parmesan-baked-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Parmesan Baked Chicken #  Ingredients #   4 5-6 oz chicken breasts 1 cup shredded provolone cheese  Ranch spread #   1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese 1/4 cup ranch dressing  Parmesan crumb topping #   1/2 cup Panko bread crumbs 1 tsp. garlic salt 1/3 shredded parmesan cheese 2 Tbsp. melted butter  Equipment Needed #   Broiler  Instructions #   Cook your chicken breasts until browned and they have an internal temperature of 165°F In a small mixing bowl, combine the grated parmesan cheese and ranch dressing In a medium mixing bowl, combine the bread crumbs, garlic salt, shredded parmesan cheese, and butter Position rack in center of the oven and preheat the broiler Place the cooked chicken breast on an oven-safe dish or tray.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strawberry Italian Ice</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/strawberry-italian-ice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:33:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/strawberry-italian-ice/</guid>
      <description>Strawberry Italian Ice #  Ingredients #   1 lb. strawberries, cleaned and pitted 1/2 cup granulated sugar 1 Tbsp. lemon juice 1/2 cup water 1-2 trays of ice cubes  Equipment Needed #   Blender  Instructions #   Blend strawberries, sugar, lemon juice, and water until the sugar dissolves Add the ice and blend until smooth Pour into a shallow pan and place into the freezer Stir the mixture every 30 minutes; this will take 2-3 hours to thoroughly freeze  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Nice Cream</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-nice-cream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Jul 2021 11:29:43 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-nice-cream/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Nice Cream #  Ingredients #   3 overripe bananas 1/4 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1/8 tsp. salt 3 Tbsp. cocoa powder  Equipment Needed #   Blender or food processor  Instructions #   Cut bananas into small rounds, put into an airtight container and freeze for 6+ hours Place all ingredenients into a food processor or blender Blend until a soft serve texture has been reached.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Buttercream</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/buttercream/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Jun 2021 09:00:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/buttercream/</guid>
      <description>Buttercream #  Makes enough buttercream for a 9-inch round 2 layer cake  Ingredients #   1 1/2 cups unsalted butter, softened 4 1/2 cups confectioners sugar 3/4 cup unsweetened cocoa powder 3 Tbsp. heavy whipping cream 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1/4 tsp. salt  Equipment Needed #   Hand or stand mixer with a paddle attachment  Instructions #   Beat the butter on medium speed for 2-3 minutes until creamy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies #  Ingredients #   1 3/4 cups flour 1/2 tsp. salt 1 tsp. baking soda 1/2 cup white sugar 1/2 cup brown sugar 1/2 cup peanut butter 1 egg 1/2 cup crisco 2 Tbsp. milk 1 tsp. vanilla 48 Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses extra white sugar for rolling  Equipment Needed #   Medium mixing bowl Mixer Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) Small bowl for sugar Large dinner plate for Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses 1 cup dry measuring cup 1/2 cup dry measuring cup 1/4 cup dry measuring cup Tablespoon Teaspoon 1/2 teaspoon Cooling racks  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375 degrees In mixing bowl, cream together the egg, white, and brown sugars, and crisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Ingredients #   1 cup shortening 2 cups white sugar 2 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 Tbsp. milk 1 15 oz. can of pumpkin 2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 1 tsp. cinnamon 3 1/2 cups of flour 1 or 2 cups of chocolate chips  Equipment Needed #   2 mixing bowls Cookie sheets  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F In a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Bread</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Bread #  Ingredients #   3 eggs 2 cups sugar 1 cup oil 2 Tbsp. vanilla 2 cups zucchini 2 cups flour 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1 tsp. salt 1 cup chopped nuts (optional)  Equipment Needed #   Two loaf pans Mixer Medium mixing bowl Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) 1 cup liquid measuring cup 1 cup dry measuring cup Tablespoon Teaspoon 1/4 teaspoon  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350 degrees In mixing bowl, beat eggs til frothy Add in sugar, oil, and vanilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Brownie Frosting</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:52:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Brownie Frosting #  Ingredients #   1/4 cup butter or margarine 6 Tbsp. cocoa powder 2 cups confectioners&#39; sugar 1/4 cup milk 1/2 tsp. of vanilla extract  Equipment Needed #   2 mixing bowls  Instructions #   Melt the butter or margarine and then mix in the cocoa powder. Set aside to cool. In another bowl, blend together the confectioners&#39; sugar, milk, and vanilla extract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Brownies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:42:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Brownies #  Ingredients #   1/2 cup vegetable oil 1 1/2 cups white sugar 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1/2 cup unsweetened cocoa powder 1 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on.  Equipment Needed #   2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Cake</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:24:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Cake #  Ingredients #   1 cup vegetable oil 2 cups sugar 3 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1 tsp. baking soda 1/2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on  Equipment Needed #   2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Not Cheeseburger Helper</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 19:17:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</guid>
      <description>Not Cheeseburger Helper #  Ingredients #   8 oz medium pasta shells 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 lb. ground beef 1/2 medium sweet onion, diced 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 1/2 tsp. Italian seasoning 2 Tbps. all-purpose flour 2 cups beef stock 15 ounces tomato sauce 3/4 cup heavy cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 6 ounces shredded extra-sharp cheddar cheese  Instructions #   In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook pasta until it is al dente according to package instructions; drain well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Feta Pasta</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 09:26:27 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</guid>
      <description>Baked Feta Pasta #  Ingredients #   8 ounces dried cavatappi pasta 2 pints cherry tomatoes 8 ounce block feta cheese 1/2 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/4 teaspoon sea salt 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 2 garlic cloves, minced 1/4 cup packed chopped fresh basil plus more for serving  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F Place the cherry tomatoes in an oven-safe baking dish. Pour in the olive oil and season with the sea salt and pepper.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Hand Pies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 20:51:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</guid>
      <description>Lazy Hand Pies #  Ingredients #   1 (9 ounce) box of Jiffy pie crust mix 1 can of pie filling in a flavor of your choosing 1 large egg 1 Tbsp. milk or water Cinnamon or demerara sugar for coating, if desired  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F Line a large baking sheet with parchment paper Prepare the pie crust mix according to the directions on the packaging On a large floured surface, roll out the pie crust until it is around 1/8 inch thick Using a 6 inch round biscuit cutter or flat rimmed bowl, cut the pie crust into 6 rounds and place them on the baking sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Pot Pulled Pork</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-pulled-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 17:39:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-pulled-pork/</guid>
      <description>Instant Pot Pulled Pork #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. packed brown sugar 2 tsp. paprika 2 tsp. garlic powder 2 tsp. onion powder 1 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pepper 1/2 tsp. cumin 1/4 tsp. cayenne 3 lbs. boneless pork roast, cut into 3-4 inch cubes 2 Tbsp. olive oil 1/3 cup apple cider vinegar 2 cups barbecue sauce, divided into 1 cup portions 1 1/4 cup beef broth, divided into 1 cup and 1/4 cup  Instructions #   In a small bowl mix together the brown sugar, paprika, garlic powder, onion powder, salt, pepper, cumin, and cayenne.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Banana Bread</title>
      <link>/docs/breads/banana-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 19:51:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/breads/banana-bread/</guid>
      <description>Banana Bread #  Makes 1 loaf or ~20 muffins  Ingredients #   3-4 ripe bananas, mashed 1/3 cup melted butter 1 cup sugar 1 egg, beaten 1 tsp. vanilla extract 1 tsp. baking soda 1/8 tsp. salt 1 1/2 cup flour 1/4 cup of chocolate chips (optional)  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Grease the loaf pan Mix together the butter and bananas Mix in eggs, sugar, and vanilla Mix in baking soda and salt Mix in flour Mix in chocolate chips Pour the mixture into the loaf pan Bake for 45 minutes  For muffins, bake for 25 minutes    Notes #   If edges are real brown and the middle is still jiggly turn the oven down to 325°F and bake in 5 minute increments until the center is no longer jiggly  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title>
      <link>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid>
      <description>Fried Chicken Sandwich #  Ingredients #   ~1 lb. boneless, skinless chicken breast 1 cup dill pickle juice 1 1/2 cups of milk, divided into 1 cup and 1/2 cup 1 3/4 cup peanut or canola oil for frying 1 large egg 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1 Tbsp. powdered sugar 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. ground black pepper  For a Spicy Chicken Sandwich #   1/2 tsp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:27:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</guid>
      <description>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake #  Ingredients #   1 lb. semisweet chocolate chips 1 lb. unsalted butter, diced 1 cup freshly brewed decaf espresso 1 cup brown sugar 8 whole eggs  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Butter 9-inch cake pan, then line the bottom of the cake pan with parchment paper. Place chocolate chips and butter into a stainless steel mixing bowl. Gently melt over double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Ziti</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:16:19 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</guid>
      <description>Baked Ziti #  Ingredients #   1 pound ziti pasta; cooked al-dente 1 Tbsp. extra virgin olive oil 1 large onion, chopped 4-6 garlic cloves, chopped 1 Tbsp. fresh rosemary or basil, minced 2 Tbsp. Italian seasoning 1/2 tsp. red pepper flakes 32 oz. marinara sauce Salt and pepper to taste 1/2 lb. of mozzarella cheese, shredded 1 cup of ricotta cheese 1 cup grated parmesan cheese  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Heat the olive oil in a large sauce pan over medium-high heat.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pasta Aglio E Olio</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:30:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</guid>
      <description>Pasta Aglio e Olio #  Ingredients #   1/2 pound of cooked linguine or fettucine pasta 1/4 cup of pasta water 5 - 6 cloves of garlic, thinly sliced 1/8 tsp. red pepper flake 1/2 cup flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped 1/2 cup olive oil 1 lemon worth of juice A pinch of kosher salt A pinch of freshly ground pepper  Instructions #   Heat the olive oil up in saucepan over medium heat Add the garlic to the saucepan and cook just until the garlic turns blonde Add the red pepper flake, salt, and pepper to the oil and stir to combine Add the pasta and pasta water to the sauce pan and toss to coat Remove the saucepan from heat Add the lemon juice and parsley to the saucepan and stir to combine  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2021 17:14:08 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/instant-pot-bbq-chicken/</guid>
      <description>Instant Pot BBQ Chicken #  Ingredients #   1 cup chicken stock 1 1/2 lbs chicken 1/4 tsp. onion powder 1/4 tsp. garlic powder 1/4 tsp. paprika 1/4 tsp. salt 3/4 cups BBQ sauce 1/4 cup grated onion, with juice 1 1/2 Tbsp. brown sugar  Instructions #   Place the ingredients in the instant pot in this order; Do NOT stir, you want the liquid to stay on the bottom of the pot so the instant pot comes to pressure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Potato Soup</title>
      <link>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Jan 2021 19:01:17 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/soups/potato-soup/</guid>
      <description>Potato Soup #  Ingredients #   6 cups of peeled and diced Russett potates (around 6 medium potatoes. Diced into cubes about 3/4 inch) 1 1/2 cups chopped yellow onion (1 medium onion) 1 1/4 cups peeled and diced carrots (3 medium or 15 baby) 1 cup diced celery (4 stalks) 29 oz low-sodium chicken broth Salt and freshly ground black pepper 1/3 cup butter 1/3 cup all-purpose flour 2 1/2 cups milk 1/2 cup sour cream  Instructions #   Combine diced potatoes, carrots, celery and onions with chicken broth in a large stockpot and season with salt and pepper to taste.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Semi Active Boy Bagel Bites</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 17:04:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/semi-active-boy-bagel-bites/</guid>
      <description>Semi-Active Boy Bagel Bites #  Ingredients #   8 Thomas&#39; Plain Mini Bagels, split Pizza sauce Cubed pepporoni Mozzeralla or a pizza cheese blend Salt Pepper  Instructions #   Adjust over rack to the middle position Preheat oven to 450°F Arrange half of the split bagels on parchment-lined baking sheet Place bagel halves in oven until their surface dries out, around 2.5 minutes Remove bagel halves from the oven and top each bagel half with pizza sauce, a sprinkle of salt, a sprinkle of pepper, a generous mound of cheese, and cubed pepperoni Bake until cheese is melted and golden brown, around 10 minutes Repeat baking steps for any remaining bagel halves  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Macaroni and Cheese</title>
      <link>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 18:23:53 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</guid>
      <description>Baked Macaroni and Cheese #  Ingredients #   16 oz cavatappi or elbow macaroni, cooked and drained 2 Tbsp. butter 4 Tbsp. flour 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. pepper 3/4 tsp. dry mustard 3 1/2 cups milk 1/4 tsp. cayenne pepper 5 cups of sharp cheddar cheese, shredded  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Pour cooked macaroni into a 3 qt. baking dish Mix flour, salt, pepper, and mustard in a small bowl and set aside Melt butter in large saucepan over low heat Stir in flour mixture into the melted butter to form a roux Raise the temperature of the saucepan to medium-high Add the milk and cayenne pepper to the saucepan and bring to a boil; while whisking until the sauce thickens.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 18:44:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/brownies/</guid>
      <description>Brownies #  Makes ~9 brownies  Ingredients #   200g (1 cup) granulated sugar 40g (1/3 cup) unsweetened cocoa powder sifted 64g (1/2 cup) all-purpose flour 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. baking powder 2 eggs, room temperature 1 tsp. McCormick vanilla 113g (1/2 cup) butter, melted then cooled  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Lightly grease an 8-inch square pan and set aside Sift together the sugar, cocoa powder, flour, salt, and baking powder into a medium bowl In another medium bowl, beat together the eggs with vanilla Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and using a whisk, stir the dry ingredients into the wet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MLTB</title>
      <link>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:58:21 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</guid>
      <description>MLTB #  Ingredients #   2 slices bread, toasted 2 slices cooked bacon, broken in half 2 slices tomato 1 slice lettuce 1/2 Tbps. mayonaise  Instructions #   Place 2 slices of bread on a cutting board. Spread mayonaise on the top slice of bread Place lettuce on the top slice Fan out the slices of bacon on the lower slice of bread Place tomatoes on the bottom slice of bread Place the top half of the sandwich onto the bottom half  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fried Pickles</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:27:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/fried-pickles/</guid>
      <description>Fried Pickles #  Ingredients #   1 16-ounce jar of kosher dill pickles, drained and dried 2/3 cup flour 1 Tbsp. of italian or Old Bay seasoning 1 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 1 egg, beaten Vegtable or canola oil for frying  Instructions #   Mix the flour, seasoning, red pepper flakes, pinch of salt, and a pinch of ground pepper in a large bowl Place the beaten egg into a small bowl, Dunk the pickles into the egg and then dredge in the flour mixture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Soft Pretzels</title>
      <link>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 13:17:32 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/appetizers/soft-pretzels/</guid>
      <description>Soft Pretzels #  Ingredients #   1 1/2 cups water, warm (~110°F) 1 Tbsp. salt 1 Tbsp. sugar 1 packet active dry yeast 4 cups (556 grams) flour 2 1/2 Tbsp. butter, melted 10 cups water 1/3 cup baking soda 1 egg yolk beaten with 1 Tbsp. of water coarse salt  Equipment Needed #   KitchenAid mixer Large stock pot  Instructions #   In the KitchenAid bowl mix the water, salt, and sugar until combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalloped Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:23:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Scalloped Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. butter 2 cloves garlic 1 Tbsp. flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 tsp. pepper 1 cup milk 3 yukon gold potatoes, peeled 2 tbsp. grated parmesan cheese  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F In a small pot, melt the butter and fry the garlic until it’s just starting to brown. Add the flour, salt and pepper. whisk until there are no lumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Big Mac Sauce</title>
      <link>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 16:25:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sauces/big-mac-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Big Mac Sauce #  Ingredients #   1/4 cup of mayonaise 1.5 tsp. sweet pickle relish 3/4 tsp. american mustard 3/4 tsp. white wine vinegar 0.5 tsp onion powder 0.5 tsp garlic powder 0.5 tsp sweet paprika  Instructions #   Place ingredients into a bowl and mix together  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chili</title>
      <link>/docs/dinner/chili/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Dec 2020 20:06:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/dinner/chili/</guid>
      <description>Chili #  Ingredients #   2 1/2 Tbsp. chili powder 2 Tbsp. ground cumin 2 Tbsp. packed light brown sugar 1 Tbsp. garlic powder 1 1/2 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. ground black pepper 1/4 tsp. ground cayenne pepper 1/8 tsp. ground cinnamon 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 medium yellow onion - diced 1 medium green bell pepper - diced 1 lb 90% lean ground beef 2 Tbsp. tomato paste 1 1/2 cups beef broth 1 (15 oz.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:20:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Baked Potatoes #  Ingredients #   Some number of russet potatoes 1.5 tsp. of olive oil Kosher salt for sprinkling on the exterior of the potatoes  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Scrub potatoes with scrub brush and dab dry Poke the potatoes 5 or 6 times with a fork Brush olive oil on the potatoes and salt the exterior lightly Place potatoes directly on the middle rack of the oven Bake for 45 - 55 minutes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies  Ingredients #   1/2 cup salted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1 large egg 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. sea salt 1 cup chocolate chips  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375°F Line a baking pan with parchment paper and set aside Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in eggs and vanilla until fluffy Mix in the dry ingredients until combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste  Instructions #   Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexy Rice</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid>
      <description>Sexy Rice #  Ingredients #   2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt  Instructions #   Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes  Notes #   When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Ganache Glaze</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Ganache Glaze #  Ingredients #   3/4 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips 3 Tbsp. butter 1 Tbsp. light corn syrup 1/3 tsp. vanilla  Instructions #   In a double boiler over hot not boiling water combine chocolate chips, margarine, and corn syrup. Stir until chips are melted and mixture is smooth. Add vanilla and stir. Use the glaze to dip cookies into or to spread over a cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Spice Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:36:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Spice Cookies #  Ingredients #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies   1 cup Crisco 1.5 cup milk 4 cups flour 0.5 cup cocoa 1.5 cup sugar 1 tsp. baking soda 3 tsp. baking powder 0.5 tsp. clove 2 tsp. cinnamon 1 tsp. allspice 3/8 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 0.25 cup chopped walnuts  Instructions #   Melt Crisco in saucepan with milk and set aside to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
