<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <link>/docs/sides/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:48:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/sides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:48:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Garlic Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   3 lb. small red potatoes 1/4 cup olive oil 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt 1 tsp. freshly ground black pepper 2 Tbsp. minced garlic  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Place the potatoes, olive oil, kosher salt, and freshly ground black pepper into a bowl. Toss until well coated.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scalloped Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:23:36 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Scalloped Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. butter 2 cloves garlic 1 Tbsp. flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 tsp. pepper 1 cup milk 3 yukon gold potatoes, peeled 2 tbsp. grated parmesan cheese  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F In a small pot, melt the butter and fry the garlic until it’s just starting to brown. Add the flour, salt and pepper. whisk until there are no lumps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baked Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:20:45 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Baked Potatoes #  Ingredients #   Some number of russet potatoes 1.5 tsp. of olive oil Kosher salt for sprinkling on the exterior of the potatoes  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Scrub potatoes with scrub brush and dab dry Poke the potatoes 5 or 6 times with a fork Brush olive oil on the potatoes and salt the exterior lightly Place potatoes directly on the middle rack of the oven Bake for 45 - 55 minutes  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste  Instructions #   Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexy Rice</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid>
      <description>Sexy Rice #  Ingredients #   2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt  Instructions #   Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes  Notes #   When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
