<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sides on Recipes</title><link>/docs/sides/</link><description>Recent content in Sides on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:35:44 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/sides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Candied Sweet Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/candied-sweet-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:35:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/candied-sweet-potatoes/</guid><description>Candied Sweet Potatoes # Ingredients # 6 yellow-fleshed sweet potatoes 1/2 cup butter or margarine 1 cup packed light brown sugar 1/2 cup water 1 tsp. salt Equipment Needed # Large pot for boiling sweet potatoes 9x13 baking dish Small sauce pan 1 cup measuring cup 1 tsp. measuring sppon Instructions # Boil whole sweet potatoes until tender (approximately 30 to 45 minutes). Drain and cool. Preheat oven to 350°F.</description></item><item><title>Deviled Eggs</title><link>/docs/sides/deviled-eggs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 19:35:44 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/deviled-eggs/</guid><description> Deviled Eggs # Ingredients # 12 large eggs, hard-boiled 3 heaping tbsp. mayonnaise or Miracle Whip 3 squirts of French&amp;rsquo;s yellow mustard Salt and pepper to taste Equipment Needed # Tbsp. measuring spoon Piping bag (optional) Large mixing bowl Instructions # Cut eggs in half, remove yolks and set aside in a mixing bowl Add mustard and mayonnaise to mixing bowl with yolks and mix together Add salt and pepper to taste Either fill the void in the eggs with dollops of the yolk mixture or pipe it into the void Refrigerate for at least an hour Serve chilled</description></item><item><title>Pasta Salad With Pepperoni</title><link>/docs/sides/pasta-salad-with-pepperoni/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 2023 18:05:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/pasta-salad-with-pepperoni/</guid><description>Pasta Salad With Pepperoni # Ingredients # 8 oz. mozzarella cheese, cubed 3/4 cup pepperoni, cubed or sliced thin 1/2 cup grated parmigiano reggiano 1 (16 oz.) package, pasta of choice, cooked and drained 8 oz. cherry tomatoes, halved 3/4 cup extra-virgin olive oil 1/2 cup red wine vinegar 3 tsp Italian seasoning 1 tsp garlic powder 1 tsp onion powder 1/2 tsp red pepper flakes, optional kosher salt and freshly ground pepper, to taste Equipment Needed # Large bowl Instructions # Combine all dry ingredients in a large bowl.</description></item><item><title>Hush Puppies</title><link>/docs/sides/hush-puppies/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2023 18:40:58 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/hush-puppies/</guid><description>Hush Puppies # Ingredients # 1 1/2 cups fine or medium grind cornmeal 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1 1/2 teaspoons kosher salt 1 1/2 teaspoons baking powder 1/2 teaspoon baking soda 1/2 teaspoon granulated sugar (optional) 1/2 small yellow onion 1 large egg 1 cup buttermilk 4 cups peanut or vegetable oil, for deep frying Equipment Needed # 1/2 cup measuring cup 1 tsp. measuring spoon 1/2 tsp. measuring spoon Whisk Spatula Box grater Large mixing bowl Dutch oven Size 40 cookie scoop Large plate Metal tongs Spider Instructions # Prepare plate for draining hush puppies.</description></item><item><title>Cottage Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/cottage-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 06 Dec 2022 14:13:18 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/cottage-potatoes/</guid><description>Cottage Potatoes # Ingredients # 2 lb bag of frozen shredded hashbrown potatoes 1/2 cup (1 stick) butter 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 teaspoon pepper 1 onion, chopped 1 can cream of mushroom soup 1 pint sour cream 1 cup shredded cheddar cheese 1 cup corn flake crumbs or shredded cheddar cheese for topping, according to preference Equipment Needed # Large saute pan 9x13 baking dish Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F In saute pan, use butter to caramelize onion.</description></item><item><title>Sage and Sausage Stuffing</title><link>/docs/sides/sage-and-sausage-stuffing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2022 07:28:56 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/sage-and-sausage-stuffing/</guid><description>Sage and Sausage Stuffing # Ingredients # 1 1/4 pounds high-quality sandwich bread or soft Italian or French bread (about 1 loaf), cut into 3/4-inch dice (about 2 1/2 quarts) 4 Tbsp. butter 3/4 pound sage sausage removed from casing 1/2 large onion, finely chopped (175g) 2 large ribs celery, finely chopped (175g) 1 clove garlic, minced or grated on a Microplane grater 1 tsp. dried sage leaves 2 cups of turkey stock divided into 1 cup portions 2 large eggs 1 Tbsp.</description></item><item><title>Baked Zucchini</title><link>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</link><pubDate>Sat, 04 Sep 2021 16:31:30 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/baked-zucchini/</guid><description>Baked Zucchini # Ingredients # 2 medium zucchini 2 eggs 1/2 cup all-purpose flour 1/4 cup grated parmesan cheese 1 cups seasoned bread crumbs Equipment Needed # Cooling rack Rimmed baking sheet Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F. Coat a cooling rack with nonstick spray and place on a rimmed baking sheet. Trim ends off zucchini and slice into 1⁄4&amp;quot; circles. Beat eggs in a small bowl or dish. In a separate bowl or dish, combine parmesan cheese, bread crumbs and salt &amp;amp; pepper to taste.</description></item><item><title>Garlic Roasted Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Aug 2021 19:48:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/garlic-roasted-potatoes/</guid><description>Garlic Roasted Potatoes # Ingredients # 3 lb. small red potatoes 1/4 cup olive oil 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt 1 tsp. freshly ground black pepper 2 Tbsp. minced garlic Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Place the potatoes, olive oil, kosher salt, and freshly ground black pepper into a bowl. Toss until well coated. Transfer the potatoes to a sheet pan and roast in the oven for 45 minutes.</description></item><item><title>Scalloped Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2020 21:23:36 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/scalloped-potatoes/</guid><description>Scalloped Potatoes # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. butter 2 cloves garlic 1 Tbsp. flour 1 teaspoon salt 1/4 tsp. pepper 1 cup milk 3 yukon gold potatoes, peeled 2 tbsp. grated parmesan cheese Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F In a small pot, melt the butter and fry the garlic until it’s just starting to brown. Add the flour, salt and pepper. whisk until there are no lumps. Slowly drizzle in the milk while constantly whisking to make sure the mixture is smooth.</description></item><item><title>Baked Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 17:20:45 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/baked-potatoes/</guid><description> Baked Potatoes # Ingredients # Some number of russet potatoes 1.5 tsp. of olive oil Kosher salt for sprinkling on the exterior of the potatoes Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F and set up a rack in the middle of the oven Scrub potatoes with scrub brush and dab dry Poke the potatoes 5 or 6 times with a fork Brush olive oil on the potatoes and salt the exterior lightly Place potatoes directly on the middle rack of the oven Bake for 45 - 55 minutes</description></item><item><title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title><link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid><description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes # Ingredients # 1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste Instructions # Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description></item><item><title>Sexy Rice</title><link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link><pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid><description>Sexy Rice # Ingredients # 2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt Instructions # Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes Notes # When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description></item></channel></rss>