<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <link>/docs/sides/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/sides/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Crispy Roasted Potatoes</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 15:39:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/crispy-roasted-potatoes/</guid>
      <description>Crispy Roasted Potatoes #  Ingredients #   1 Tbsp. kosher salt 1/4 tsp. baking soda 2 pounds of peeled russet potatoes cut into quarters, sixths, or eighths, depending on size 2.5 Tbsp. of extra-virgin olive oil 3 medium cloves of garlic, minced Additional kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper to taste  Instructions #   Adjust oven rack to center position and preheat to 450°F (400°F in convection oven) Bring 2 quarts of water to a boil over high heat Add kosher salt, baking soda, and potatoes to water and stir.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sexy Rice</title>
      <link>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 11:24:23 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/sides/sexy-rice/</guid>
      <description>Sexy Rice #  Ingredients #   2 cups of rice 3 cups water 2 Tbsp. of butter 2 heavy pinches of kosher salt  Instructions #   Bring water to a boil in an electric kettle Saute the rice in a pot over high heat with butter and salt Place a lid on the rice pot; add a piece of foil for loose lids Turn off the heat Tilt the lid of the pot slightly and pour the boiled water into the pot and lower the lid; be careful of steam Turn the heat to the lowest setting Wait 20 minutes Turn the heat off Remove the lid and fluff the rice with a fork to release the steam Let rest for 2 minutes  Notes #   When heating up, place a small amount of water in the bottom of the vessel the rice is being heated up in.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
