<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sandwiches on Recipes</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/</link><description>Recent content in Sandwiches on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:21:20 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/sandwiches/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Slow Cooker French Dip Sandwiches</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 08:21:20 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches">
 Slow Cooker French Dip Sandwiches
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#slow-cooker-french-dip-sandwiches">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">
 Ingredients
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#ingredients">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 1/2 cups low-sodium beef broth&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/4 cup low sodium soy sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 Tbsp Worcestershire sauce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 tsp honey&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 lbs chuck roast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Salt and freshly ground black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 Tbsp olive oil&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 sprig fresh rosemary&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 sprig fresh thyme (use a big sprig with several stems)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large yellow onion, sliced&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 cloves garlic, minced (2 Tbsp)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 Crusty hoagie buns (smaller ones) or 2 crusty baguettes cut into thirds&lt;/li>
&lt;li>3 Tbsp butter&lt;/li>
&lt;li>6 deli slices provolone or swiss cheese halved&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="equipment-needed">
 Equipment Needed
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#equipment-needed">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>6 qt. slow cooker&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 cup measuring cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp. measuring spoon&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp measuring spoon&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instructions">
 Instructions
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#instructions">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>In a bowl (or large liquid measuring cup used to measure broth), whisk together broth, soy sauce, Worcestershire and honey, set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Heat olive oil in a large pot over medium-high heat. Dab both sides of roast dry with paper towels, season just lightly with salt and a fair amount of pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Sear roast in pot until browned on both sides, about 3 minutes per side. Transfer roast to a 5 to 7 quart slow cooker, while leaving oil in pot.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Add onion to pot and saute 3 minutes, add garlic and saute 30 seconds longer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove pot from heat, pour beef broth mixture into pot and scrape any browned bits from the bottom. Pour mixture into slow cooker over roast.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Submerge rosemary and thyme spring into broth on sides of roast. Cover and cook on low 8 hours.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Remove roast from slow cooker and transfer to a cutting board, while leaving behind onions and herbs. Shred roast with two forks while removing excess fat.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>If needed season broth and beef with a little salt, if you find it a little too salty for your liking add in a little water to broth mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Pour broth mixture in slow cooker through a fine mesh sieve into a bowl and discard mixture in sieve.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Return roast to now empty slow cooker, toss with 1/3 cup of the strained broth mixture.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>For buns, heat oven to 350 degrees (or a countertop toaster oven works great here if you have one). Cut buns through the center, place buns cut side up on a rimmed baking sheet.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread butter on each side then toast in preheated oven about 7 - 8 minutes, add cheese to one of of each bun and toast until melted, about 2 minutes longer.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Layer beef over rolls and top with remaining half. Serve warm with remaining broth for dipping.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Fried Chicken Sandwich</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</link><pubDate>Sat, 27 Feb 2021 15:30:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/fried-chicken-sandwich/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="fried-chicken-sandwich">
 Fried Chicken Sandwich
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#fried-chicken-sandwich">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">
 Ingredients
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#ingredients">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>~1 lb. boneless, skinless chicken breast&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 cup dill pickle juice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 1/2 cups of milk, divided into 1 cup and 1/2 cup&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 3/4 cup peanut or canola oil for frying&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 large egg&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 cup all-purpose flour&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp. powdered sugar&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 tsp. salt&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp. ground black pepper&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h3 id="for-a-spicy-chicken-sandwich">
 For a Spicy Chicken Sandwich
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#for-a-spicy-chicken-sandwich">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h3>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>1/2 tsp. paprika&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 Tbsp. cayenne powder&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instructions">
 Instructions
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#instructions">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Butterfly the chicken breast. Then using the flat side of a meat tenderizer, pound the chicken until ~1/2 inch thick all around.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Cut the chicken into 4 equally sized pieces.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large shallow baking dish, combine chicken, pickle juice, and 1/2 cup of milk. Marinate for 30-60 minutes, and then drain well.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>In a large cast-iron skillet, heat the oil to 350°F.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Set up your dredging station using 2 shallow baking dishes. In the first whisk together 1 cup of milk and 1 large egg. And in the second combine the flour, powdered sugar, salt, and pepper.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>To coat the chicken, first dip the chicken into the milk and egg mixture and then drain the excess. Then dredge the chicken in the flour mixture and set aside for 2-3 minutes. After 2-3 minutes, dredge the chicken once more in the flour mixure and set aside.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fry each piece of chicken in the skillet for 2-3 minutes on each side until golden brown. Remove from skillet and drain excess oil from chicken.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Serve chicken on a hamburger bun that has been lightly toasted with butter. Place 2-3 pickles on the heel of the bun, followed by the chicken, and then place the crown of the bun on top.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>MLTB</title><link>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2021 19:58:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/sandwiches/mltb/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="mltb">
 MLTB
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#mltb">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h1>
&lt;h2 id="ingredients">
 Ingredients
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#ingredients">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>2 slices bread, toasted&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 slices cooked bacon, broken in half&lt;/li>
&lt;li>2 slices tomato&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1 slice lettuce&lt;/li>
&lt;li>1/2 Tbps. mayonaise&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;h2 id="instructions">
 Instructions
 &lt;a class="anchor" href="#instructions">#&lt;/a>
&lt;/h2>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Place 2 slices of bread on a cutting board.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Spread mayonaise on the top slice of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place lettuce on the top slice&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Fan out the slices of bacon on the lower slice of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place tomatoes on the bottom slice of bread&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Place the top half of the sandwich onto the bottom half&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item></channel></rss>