<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pastas on Recipes</title><link>/docs/pastas/</link><description>Recent content in Pastas on Recipes</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 17:50:29 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/pastas/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Burst Cherry Tomato Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/burst-cherry-tomato-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 17:50:29 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/burst-cherry-tomato-pasta/</guid><description>Burst Cherry Tomato Pasta # Ingredients # 1/2 cup extra-virgin olive oil, plus more for drizzling 6 garlic cloves, smashed 2 1/2 lb. cherry tomatoes (about 4 pints) 2 large sprigs basil, plus 1 cup basil leaves, torn if large 3/4 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 1 1/2 tsp. kosher salt, plus more Pinch of sugar (optional) 12 oz. casarecce or other medium-size pasta 1 oz. Parmesan, finely grated (about ½ cup), plus more for serving Equipment Needed # 2 large pots Instructions # Heat /1 cup oil in a large heavy pot over low.</description></item><item><title>Parmesan Spinach Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/parmesan-spinach-pasta/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Feb 2022 21:21:05 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/parmesan-spinach-pasta/</guid><description>Parmesan Spinach Pasta # Ingredients # 1 13.25 oz package thin spaghetti 8 Tbsp. extra-virgin olive oil, divided into 1 and 7 Tbsp. 2 garlic cloves, minced 1/2 tsp. crushed red pepper flakes 6 cups spinach 4 Tbsp. lemon juice 1/2 cup parmesan cheese 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. pepper Instructions # Cook and drain pasta per package instructions to al dente Add 1 Tbsp. olive oil into the pot the pasta was cooked in.</description></item><item><title>Not Cheeseburger Helper</title><link>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Apr 2021 19:17:15 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/not-cheeseburger-helper/</guid><description>Not Cheeseburger Helper # Ingredients # 8 oz medium pasta shells 1 Tbsp. olive oil 1 lb. ground beef 1/2 medium sweet onion, diced 2 cloves garlic, minced 1 1/2 tsp. Italian seasoning 2 Tbps. all-purpose flour 2 cups beef stock 15 ounces tomato sauce 3/4 cup heavy cream Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper, to taste 6 ounces shredded extra-sharp cheddar cheese Instructions # In a large pot of boiling salted water, cook pasta until it is al dente according to package instructions; drain well.</description></item><item><title>Baked Feta Pasta</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 09:26:27 -0400</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-feta-pasta/</guid><description>Baked Feta Pasta # Ingredients # 8 ounces dried cavatappi pasta 2 pints cherry tomatoes 8 ounce block feta cheese 1/2 cup extra virgin olive oil 1/4 teaspoon sea salt 1/4 teaspoon black pepper 2 garlic cloves, minced 1/4 cup packed chopped fresh basil plus more for serving Instructions # Preheat oven to 400°F Place the cherry tomatoes in an oven-safe baking dish. Pour in the olive oil and season with the sea salt and pepper.</description></item><item><title>Baked Ziti</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</link><pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:16:19 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-ziti/</guid><description>Baked Ziti # Ingredients # 1 pound ziti pasta; cooked al-dente 1 Tbsp. extra virgin olive oil 1 large onion, chopped 4-6 garlic cloves, chopped 1 Tbsp. fresh rosemary or basil, minced 2 Tbsp. Italian seasoning 1/2 tsp. red pepper flakes 32 oz. marinara sauce Salt and pepper to taste 1/2 lb. of mozzarella cheese, shredded 1 cup of ricotta cheese 1 cup grated parmesan cheese Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Heat the olive oil in a large sauce pan over medium-high heat.</description></item><item><title>Pasta Aglio E Olio</title><link>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 12:30:21 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/pasta-aglio-e-olio/</guid><description> Pasta Aglio e Olio # Ingredients # 1/2 pound of cooked linguine or fettucine pasta 1/4 cup of pasta water 5 - 6 cloves of garlic, thinly sliced 1/8 tsp. red pepper flake 1/2 cup flat-leaf parsley, finely chopped 1/2 cup olive oil 1 lemon worth of juice A pinch of kosher salt A pinch of freshly ground pepper Instructions # Heat the olive oil up in saucepan over medium heat Add the garlic to the saucepan and cook just until the garlic turns blonde Add the red pepper flake, salt, and pepper to the oil and stir to combine Add the pasta and pasta water to the sauce pan and toss to coat Remove the saucepan from heat Add the lemon juice and parsley to the saucepan and stir to combine</description></item><item><title>Baked Macaroni and Cheese</title><link>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2021 18:23:53 -0500</pubDate><guid>/docs/pastas/baked-macaroni-and-cheese/</guid><description>Baked Macaroni and Cheese # Ingredients # 16 oz cavatappi or elbow macaroni, cooked and drained 2 Tbsp. butter 4 Tbsp. flour 1 tsp. salt 1/2 tsp. pepper 3/4 tsp. dry mustard 3 1/2 cups milk 1/4 tsp. cayenne pepper 5 cups of sharp cheddar cheese, shredded Instructions # Preheat oven to 350°F Pour cooked macaroni into a 3 qt. baking dish Mix flour, salt, pepper, and mustard in a small bowl and set aside Melt butter in large saucepan over low heat Stir in flour mixture into the melted butter to form a roux Raise the temperature of the saucepan to medium-high Add the milk and cayenne pepper to the saucepan and bring to a boil; while whisking until the sauce thickens.</description></item></channel></rss>