<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <link>/docs/desserts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/desserts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies  Ingredients #   1/2 cup salted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1 large egg 1.5 cups all-purpose flower 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. sea salt 1 cup chocolate chips  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375°F Line a baking pan with parchment paper and set aside Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in eggs and vanilla until fluffy Min in the dry ingredients until combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Glaze</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-glaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-glaze/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Glaze #  Ingredients #   3/4 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips 3 Tbsp. margarine 1 Tbsp. light corn syrup 1/3 tsp. vanilla  Instructions #   In a double boiler, over hot not boiling water, combine combine chocolate chips; margarine; &amp;amp; corn syrup. Stir until chips are melted &amp;amp; mixture is smooth. Add vanilla and stir. Use the glaze to dip cookies or spread over a cake.  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Spice Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:36:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Spice Cookies #  Ingredients #  Makes ~6 dozen cookies   8 cups flour 1 cup cocoa 3 cup sugar 2 tsp. baking soda 6 tsp. baking powder 1 tsp. clove 1 lb. chopped walnuts 4 tsp. cinnamon 2 tsp. allspice 3/4 tsp. salt 2 tsp. vanilla 2 cup Crisco 3 cup milk  Instructions #   Melt Crisco in saucepan with milk and set aside to cool Mix dry ingredients Gradually stir dry ingredients iinto cooled Crisco and milk Stir in the chopped walnuts Set dough aside to settle Preheat oven to 400°F Roll dough into walnut sized balls Bake for 10 minutes Set aside to cool Dip in chocolate glaze  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
