<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes</title>
    <link>/docs/desserts/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Recipes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/docs/desserts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/peanut-butter-kiss-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Peanut Butter Kiss Cookies #  Ingredients #   1 3/4 cups flour 1/2 tsp. salt 1 tsp. baking soda 1/2 cup white sugar 1/2 cup brown sugar 1/2 cup peanut butter 1 egg 1/2 cup crisco 2 Tbsp. milk 1 tsp. vanilla 48 Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses extra white sugar for rolling  Equipment Needed #   Medium mixing bowl Mixer Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) Small bowl for sugar Large dinner plate for Hershey&amp;rsquo;s kisses 1 cup dry measuring cup 1/2 cup dry measuring cup 1/4 cup dry measuring cup Tablespoon Teaspoon 1/2 teaspoon Cooling racks  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375 degrees In mixing bowl, cream together the egg, white, and brown sugars, and crisco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/pumpkin-chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Pumpkin Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Ingredients #   1 cup shortening 2 cups white sugar 2 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 Tbsp. milk 1 15 oz. can of pumpkin 2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 1 tsp. cinnamon 3 1/2 cups of flour 1 or 2 cups of chocolate chips  Equipment Needed #   2 mixing bowls Cookie sheets  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F In a mixing bowl.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Bread</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 09:01:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-bread/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Bread #  Ingredients #   3 eggs 2 cups sugar 1 cup oil 2 Tbsp. vanilla 2 cups zucchini 2 cups flour 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1 tsp. salt 1 cup chopped nuts (optional)  Equipment Needed #   Two loaf pans Mixer Medium mixing bowl Large mixing bowl (if not using stand mixer) 1 cup liquid measuring cup 1 cup dry measuring cup Tablespoon Teaspoon 1/4 teaspoon  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350 degrees In mixing bowl, beat eggs til frothy Add in sugar, oil, and vanilla.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Brownie Frosting</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:52:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-brownie-frosting/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Brownie Frosting #  Ingredients #   1/4 cup butter or margarine 6 Tbsp. cocoa powder 2 cups confectioners&#39; sugar 1/4 cup milk 1/2 tsp. of vanilla extract  Equipment Needed #   2 mixing bowls  Instructions #   Melt the butter or margarine and then mix in the cocoa powder. Set aside to cool. In another bowl, blend together the confectioners&#39; sugar, milk, and vanilla extract.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Brownies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:42:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-brownies/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Brownies #  Ingredients #   1/2 cup vegetable oil 1 1/2 cups white sugar 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1/2 cup unsweetened cocoa powder 1 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1 tsp. salt 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on.  Equipment Needed #   2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zucchini Cake</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 May 2021 08:24:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/zucchini-cake/</guid>
      <description>Zucchini Cake #  Ingredients #   1 cup vegetable oil 2 cups sugar 3 large eggs 2 tsp. vanilla extract 2 cups flour 1 tsp. baking soda 1/2 tsp. baking powder 2 tsp. cinnamon 2 cups shredded zucchini. Cleaned with skin on  Equipment Needed #   2 large mixing bowls 9&amp;quot; x 13&amp;quot; x 2&amp;quot; baking pan  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Grease and flour the baking pan and set aside.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lazy Hand Pies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Apr 2021 20:51:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/lazy-hand-pies/</guid>
      <description>Lazy Hand Pies #  Ingredients #   1 (9 ounce) box of Jiffy pie crust mix 1 can of pie filling in a flavor of your choosing 1 large egg 1 Tbsp. milk or water Cinnamon or demerara sugar for coating, if desired  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 400°F Line a large baking sheet with parchment paper Prepare the pie crust mix according to the directions on the packaging On a large floured surface, roll out the pie crust until it is around 1/8 inch thick Using a 6 inch round biscuit cutter or flat rimmed bowl, cut the pie crust into 6 rounds and place them on the baking sheet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 19:27:02 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/flourless-chocolate-espresso-cake/</guid>
      <description>Flourless Chocolate Espresso Cake #  Ingredients #   1 lb. semisweet chocolate chips 1 lb. unsalted butter, diced 1 cup freshly brewed decaf espresso 1 cup brown sugar 8 whole eggs  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Butter 9-inch cake pan, then line the bottom of the cake pan with parchment paper. Place chocolate chips and butter into a stainless steel mixing bowl. Gently melt over double boiler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Brownies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/brownies/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Jan 2021 18:44:27 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/brownies/</guid>
      <description>Brownies #  Makes ~9 brownies  Ingredients #   200g (1 cup) granulated sugar 40g (1/3 cup) unsweetened cocoa powder sifted 64g (1/2 cup) all-purpose flour 1/4 tsp. salt 1/4 tsp. baking powder 2 eggs, room temperature 1 tsp. McCormick vanilla 113g (1/2 cup) butter, melted then cooled  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 350°F Lightly grease an 8-inch square pan and set aside Sift together the sugar, cocoa powder, flour, salt, and baking powder into a medium bowl In another medium bowl, beat together the eggs with vanilla Add the dry ingredients to the wet ingredients and using a whisk, stir the dry ingredients into the wet.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Chip Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Dec 2020 20:59:56 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-chip-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Chip Cookies #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies  Ingredients #   1/2 cup salted butter (softened) 1/2 cup granulated white sugar 1/2 cup packed light brown sugar 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 1 large egg 1 1/2 cups all-purpose flour 1/2 tsp. baking soda 1/4 tsp. baking powder 1/4 tsp. sea salt 1 cup chocolate chips  Instructions #   Preheat oven to 375°F Line a baking pan with parchment paper and set aside Cream together butter and sugars until combined Beat in eggs and vanilla until fluffy Mix in the dry ingredients until combined.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Ganache Glaze</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 20:00:06 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-ganache-glaze/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Ganache Glaze #  Ingredients #   3/4 cup semi-sweet chocolate chips 3 Tbsp. butter 1 Tbsp. light corn syrup 1/3 tsp. vanilla  Instructions #   In a double boiler over hot not boiling water combine chocolate chips, margarine, and corn syrup. Stir until chips are melted and mixture is smooth. Add vanilla and stir. Use the glaze to dip cookies into or to spread over a cake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chocolate Spice Cookies</title>
      <link>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2020 19:36:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/docs/desserts/chocolate-spice-cookies/</guid>
      <description>Chocolate Spice Cookies #  Ingredients #  Makes ~3 dozen cookies   1 cup Crisco 1.5 cup milk 4 cups flour 0.5 cup cocoa 1.5 cup sugar 1 tsp. baking soda 3 tsp. baking powder 0.5 tsp. clove 2 tsp. cinnamon 1 tsp. allspice 3/8 tsp. salt 1 tsp. pure vanilla extract 0.25 cup chopped walnuts  Instructions #   Melt Crisco in saucepan with milk and set aside to cool.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
